<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ratts rhimed to death. Or, The Rump-Parliament hang'd up in the Shambles.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1659</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 119 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 49 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A92175</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R307</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1761_2</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R203305</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99863294</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99863294</idno>
            <idno type="VID">115486</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A92175)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 115486)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 219:E1761[2])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Ratts rhimed to death. Or, The Rump-Parliament hang'd up in the Shambles.</title>
                  <author>Brome, Alexander, 1620-1666.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[8], 89, [3] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year 1660 [i.e. 1659]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Edited by Alexander Brome.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>The first leaf and the last leaf are blank.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Nouemb: 1659".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament --  Humor --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Political ballads and songs --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1649-1660 --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:115486:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>RATTS Rhimed to Death. OR, THE Rump-Parliament Hang'd up in the SHAMBLES.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the Year 1660.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:115486:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:115486:2"/>
            <head>TO THE READER.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>READER,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>His Collection of ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent Ballads on the late <hi>RUMP,</hi> who called them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves the <hi>Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> when they were formerly Printed in looſe ſheets, might not unfitly be called the Picture of the Members of the <hi>Rump</hi> diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved, and ſtinking ſingly a-part. Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing now bound together, they may as fit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly be called the Picture of the ſaid
<pb facs="tcp:115486:3"/> 
               <hi>Rump</hi> aſſembled, and stinking in Conſort. If you think this ſecond Edi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion might be ſpared, I muſt borrow my Apology from their Sermons, who were Preachers to the Rump; which, for the most part, were nothing but Repetition and Tautology, or a Rump of ſtaler Mutton haſh'd by ill looks, where all the parts being minced exceeding ſmall, loſt their order and diſtinction. And where that which was the Preface would as well have ſerved for the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluſion; and both the Preface and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluſion would equally have past for the Middle of the dry Diſcourſe. If you ask me, Why being dead and rotten, the unſavoury remembrance of them is preſerved by theſe Papers: It is, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe whilst they lived, they were a kind of Purrezes, whoſe buſineſs was to ſuck the blood of the Nation, and to break our ſleeps by ſtinging; and who
<pb facs="tcp:115486:3"/> never ſtink more than when they are cruſht, and ſqueezed; and who, in ſpight of all perfumes, will offend the Noſe even when they are dead. I hope you will pardon the ill Tunes to which they are to be ſung, there being none bad enough for them; nor any voice ſo fit as their Speaker's, who, as long as he was the Rump of this Rump, and ſate in the Chair, it was a kind of a new Common-wealth, or Mr. <hi>Hobs</hi>'s Artifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciall Man made a <hi>Leviathan,</hi> ſtill breaking wind, and ſpeaking backwards.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="collection">
            <pb facs="tcp:115486:4"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:115486:4"/>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>ARSY VERSY: OR, The ſecond Martyrdom of the <hi>RUMP.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>The blind Beggar of Bednal-green.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg n="1">
                  <head>1.</head>
                  <l>MY Muſe to prevent leſt an after-clap come,</l>
                  <l>If the wind ſhould once more turn about for the Bum,</l>
                  <l>As a Preface of Honor, and not as a Frump,</l>
                  <l>Firſt with a Sirreverence uſhers the <hi>Rump.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="2">
                  <head>2.</head>
                  <l>I ſhall not diſpute whether Long-tails of <hi>Kent,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or Papiſts, this name of diſgrace did invent;</l>
                  <l>Whoſe Legend of Lies, to defame us the more,</l>
                  <l>Hath entail'd on us <hi>Rumps</hi> ne're heard on before.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="3">
                  <head>3.</head>
                  <l>But not on its Pedigree longer to think,</l>
                  <l>(For the more it is ſtirr'd the more it will ſtink)</l>
                  <l>'Tis agreed the <hi>Rump</hi>'s firſt report in the Town</l>
                  <l>Did ariſe from the woodden invention of <hi>Brown.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:115486:5"/>
               <lg n="4">
                  <head>4.</head>
                  <l>Old <hi>Oliver</hi>'s noſe had taken in ſnuff,</l>
                  <l>When it ſate long ago, ſome unſavoury puffe;</l>
                  <l>Then up went the <hi>Rump,</hi> and was <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>kt to the quick;</l>
                  <l>But it ſetled in ſpight of the teeth of poor <hi>Dick.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="5">
                  <head>5.</head>
                  <l>Then the Knight of the Peſtle, King <hi>Lambert</hi> and <hi>Vane,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With a Scepter of Iron did over it reign:</l>
                  <l>But the <hi>Rump</hi> ſoon re-ſetled, and to their diſgrace,</l>
                  <l>Like Excrements voided them out of the place.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="6">
                  <head>6.</head>
                  <l>It did now, like a Truant's well diſciplin'd Bum,</l>
                  <l>With the Rod affliction harder become;</l>
                  <l>Or elſe like the Image in <hi>Daniel</hi> it was,</l>
                  <l>Whoſe head was of Gold, but whoſe tail was of Braſſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="7">
                  <head>7.</head>
                  <l>It endur'd the firſt heat, and prov'd no ſtarter,</l>
                  <l>But ſung in the midſt of the flames like a Martyr,</l>
                  <l>And whisk'd the tail like a terrible Farter,</l>
                  <l>And ſounded moſt cheerfully, <hi>Vive Sir Arthur.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="8">
                  <head>8.</head>
                  <l>But the next fire-Ordeal put into a dump,</l>
                  <l>Sir <hi>Orlando</hi> the furious chief joynt of the <hi>Rump,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That he lookt like the picture of <hi>Richard</hi> the Third,</l>
                  <l>Or like an ejected and froſt-bitten t—</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="9">
                  <head>9.</head>
                  <l>'Tis ſaid that his <hi>Durindana</hi> he drew,</l>
                  <l>And a Wight on the Road moſt manfully ſlew;</l>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:115486:5"/>
                  <l>But, pardon'd by <hi>Charls,</hi> made good what they tell us,</l>
                  <l>How ill 'tis to ſave a Thief from the Gallows.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="10">
                  <head>10.</head>
                  <l>Being now to be burnt, he ſoon did expire,</l>
                  <l>For he was but a flaſh and would quickly take fire;</l>
                  <l>So that their fewell upon him to ſpend,</l>
                  <l>What was it but Coals to <hi>Newcastle</hi> to ſend?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="11">
                  <head>11.</head>
                  <l>To bring 'em to th'ſtake as in order they lie,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Harry Martin</hi> the next place muſt occupy;</l>
                  <l>'Twas expected in vain he ſhould blaze, for he ſwore,</l>
                  <l>That he had been burnt to the ſtumps before.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="12">
                  <head>12.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom Scot</hi> for the <hi>Bum</hi> moſt ſtiffly did ſtand,</l>
                  <l>Though once by a <hi>Bum</hi> he was fouly trapand;</l>
                  <l>But Time and his Office of <hi>Secretary</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Had learnt him his buſineſſe more private to carry.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="13">
                  <head>13.</head>
                  <l>Some thought he arriv'd at his dignity firſt,</l>
                  <l>By being ſo well in iniquity verſt;</l>
                  <l>The myſterie of which he hath practis'd of late</l>
                  <l>In his function, which was, to be Bawd to the State.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="14">
                  <head>14.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Hob Morley</hi> in ſilence did ſuffer the loſſe</l>
                  <l>Of his <hi>Rump,</hi> and with patience took up the Croſſe;</l>
                  <l>That to ſee him ſo ſindg'd and ſo ſcorcht you would ſwear,</l>
                  <l>No Camell more meekly his burden could bear.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:115486:6"/>
               <lg n="15">
                  <head>15.</head>
                  <l>The <hi>Speaker</hi> was thought to the <hi>Rump</hi> to be true,</l>
                  <l>Becauſe like a Fart at the firſt he burnt blew;</l>
                  <l>But ſtreight he was cunningly ſeen to retire,</l>
                  <l>For fear to endanger the Rolls in the fire.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="16">
                  <head>16.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>St. John</hi> a mortall of fleſh and of bloood,</l>
                  <l>Swore by St. <note n="*" place="bottom">He hath a great kindneſſe for that Saint, not becauſe of his Key, (which he knows he ſhall never make uſe of) but in refe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence to <hi>Peterborovgh</hi> Minſter, the ſtones of which built his new Houſe.</note> 
                     <hi>Peter</hi> the example was good:</l>
                  <l>So facing about, and ſhifting his ſtation,</l>
                  <l>He turn'd o're a new leaf in <hi>St. John</hi>'s Revelation.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="17">
                  <head>17.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Harry Nevill</hi> that looks like a <hi>Mahomet</hi>'s Pidgeon,</l>
                  <l>Accuſed to be of a State-man's Religion,</l>
                  <l>Is left to his choice what Proceſſe he'l have,</l>
                  <l>To be burnt for an Atheiſt, or hang'd for a Knave.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="18">
                  <head>18.</head>
                  <l>Now ſtop thy noſe, Reader, for <hi>Atkins</hi> does come,</l>
                  <l>That ſhame to the Breeches as well as the <hi>Bum:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To wiſh he were burnt were an idle deſire,</l>
                  <l>For he comes provided to ſhite out the fire.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="19">
                  <head>19.</head>
                  <l>But leſt he without a companion ſhould be,</l>
                  <l>Here's <hi>Liſle</hi> that comes next ſtinks worſer than he;</l>
                  <l>So fouly corrupt, you may place't in your Creed,</l>
                  <l>Such a <hi>Rump</hi> could alone ſuch a Fiſtula breed.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:115486:6"/>
               <lg n="20">
                  <head>20.</head>
                  <l>Poor <hi>Ludlow</hi> was bogg'd in <hi>Ireland</hi> of late,</l>
                  <l>And to purge himſelf came to the <hi>Rump</hi> of the State;</l>
                  <l>But gravely they told him he had acted amiſs,</l>
                  <l>When he ſought to betray the <hi>Rump</hi> with a kiſſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="21">
                  <head>21.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ned Harby</hi> was ſure an herb <hi>John</hi> in the pot,</l>
                  <l>Yet could he not ſcape the dyſaſterous lot:</l>
                  <l>Scarce Church'd of the Gowt was the truſty old Squire,</l>
                  <l>But he hopt from the frying-pan into the fire.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="22">
                  <head>22.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Andrews</hi> was laid on laſt, as they tell us,</l>
                  <l>For a Log to keep down the reſt of his fellows;</l>
                  <l>Though he ſpent on the City like one of the Royſters</l>
                  <l>Each morning his <note n="*" place="bottom">Some Authors hold it was but three half-pence, but poetry will not admit of broken numbers.</note> two-pence in Sack &amp; in Oyſters.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="23">
                  <head>23.</head>
                  <l>Next <hi>Praiſe-God,</hi> although of the <hi>Rump</hi> he was none,</l>
                  <l>Was for his Petition burnt to the <hi>Bare-bone:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So <hi>Praiſe-God</hi> and <hi>Rump,</hi> like true <hi>Joſephs</hi> together,</l>
                  <l>Did ſuffer; but <hi>Praiſe-God</hi> loſt the more <note n="*" place="bottom">Courteous Reader, he is a Leather-ſeller.</note> Leather.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="24">
                  <head>24.</head>
                  <l>There's <hi>Lawſon</hi> another dag-lock of the Tail,</l>
                  <l>That the fire to avoid to the water did ſail;</l>
                  <l>And in godly ſimplicity means (as they ſay)</l>
                  <l>To manage the Stern, though the <hi>Rump</hi>'s out of play.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:115486:7"/>
               <lg n="25">
                  <head>25.</head>
                  <l>But <hi>Overton</hi> moſt with wonder doth ſeize us,</l>
                  <l>By ſecuring of <hi>Hull</hi> for no leſſe than Chriſt Jeſus,</l>
                  <l>Hoping (as it by the ſtory appears)</l>
                  <l>To be there his Lieutenant for one thouſand years.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="26">
                  <head>26.</head>
                  <l>Lord <hi>Monſon?</hi> Oh <hi>Venus!</hi> what do you hear?</l>
                  <l>I little thought you were a <hi>Rumper</hi> I ſwear:</l>
                  <l>But an impotent Lord will thus far avail,</l>
                  <l>He will ſerve for a cloak to cover the tail.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="27">
                  <head>27.</head>
                  <l>To burniſh his Star Mr. <hi>Salsbury</hi>'s come,</l>
                  <l>With the Atoms of gold that fall from the <hi>Bum;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Sure 'twas but a Meteor, for I muſt tell ye,</l>
                  <l>It ſmells as 'twere turning to the Alderman's jelly.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="28">
                  <head>28.</head>
                  <l>Brother <hi>Pembrook</hi> comes laſt, and does not diſdain,</l>
                  <l>Though deſpis'd by the world, to bear up the train;</l>
                  <l>But after new lights ſo long he did run,</l>
                  <l>That they brought him to <note n="*" place="bottom">Not <hi>Bethlehem</hi> in <hi>Iudea,</hi> (for he is none of the <hi>Magi.</hi>)</note> 
                     <hi>Bethlehem</hi> before they had done.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="29">
                  <head>29.</head>
                  <l>Thus the <hi>Foxes</hi> of <hi>Sampſon</hi> that carried a Brand</l>
                  <l>In their tails, to deſtroy and to burn up the Land;</l>
                  <l>In the flames they had kindled themſelves do expire,</l>
                  <l>And the Dee'l give them brimſtone unto their fire.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:115486:7"/>
               <head>RUMP RAMPANT, Or, The ſweet Old Cauſe in ſippits: Set out by Sir <hi>T. A.</hi> Perfumer to his late Highneſſe.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>Laſt Parliament ſat as ſnugg as a Cat.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>IN the name of the Fiend, what the Rump up agin!</l>
                  <l>The Delk, and the good old cauſe!</l>
                  <l>If they ſettle agin, which to think were a ſin,</l>
                  <l>Good-night to Religion and Laws.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Firſt, Tithes muſt go down like a ſprig of the Crown,</l>
                  <l>Although John Presbyter grumble;</l>
                  <l>Already they tell's our Lead and our Bells</l>
                  <l>They'l ſell, next our Churches muſt tumble.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This poor <hi>Engliſh</hi> Nation, by this Generation</l>
                  <l>Hath been griev'd 11. years and more,</l>
                  <l>But in that ſeaſon, and not without reaſon,</l>
                  <l>They ha' thrice been turn'd out of door.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Which they pleaſe to call <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>orce, yet themſelves can do worſe;</l>
                  <l>For this Parcel of a Houſe</l>
                  <pb n="8" facs="tcp:115486:8"/>
                  <l>Dare keep out of door, thrice as many more,</l>
                  <l>And value the Law not a Louſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Firſt by Owl-light they met, and by that light they ſet:</l>
                  <l>The reaſon of it mark,</l>
                  <l>Their acts and the light, do differ quite,</l>
                  <l>Their deeds do beſt with the dark.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Eſquire <hi>Lenthall</hi> had ſwore, he'd ſit there no more,</l>
                  <l>Unleſſe in with Oxen they drew him;</l>
                  <l>That he once might ſpeak true, they pick'd him out two,</l>
                  <l>Sent <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Salisbury</hi> to him.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When theſe Gamſters were pack'd, the firſt gracious act</l>
                  <l>Was for pence for their friends of the Army:</l>
                  <l>Who for any ſide fight, except't be the right;</l>
                  <l>Sixſcore thouſand a month won't harm ye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet many there be, ſay The Houſe is not free,</l>
                  <l>When I am ſure of that,</l>
                  <l>T' one another they 're ſo free, that the Nation do ſee,</l>
                  <l>They 're too free for us to be fat.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Religion they wav'd, now they had us enſlav'd</l>
                  <l>And got us ſure in their Claw:</l>
                  <l>They puld off their mask, and ſet us our task,</l>
                  <l>Which is next to make Brick without Straw.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The next Act they made, was for helping of Trade,</l>
                  <l>So they ſetled again the Exciſe,</l>
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:115486:8"/>
                  <l>Which the City muſt pay, for ever and aye,</l>
                  <l>Yet might have choſe had they been wiſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>To pull down their King, their plate they could bring,</l>
                  <l>And other precious things:</l>
                  <l>So that <hi>Sedgwick</hi> and <hi>Peters,</hi> were no ſmall getters</l>
                  <l>By their Bodkins, Thimbles, and Rings.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when for the good of the Nation 'twas ſtood,</l>
                  <l>Half ruined and forlorn,</l>
                  <l>Though't lay in their power, to redeem 't in an hour,</l>
                  <l>Not a Citizen put out his horn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They had manacled their hands, with King's and Biſhop's Lands,</l>
                  <l>And ruin'd the whole Nation,</l>
                  <l>So that no body cares, though they and their heirs</l>
                  <l>Be Cornute to the third generation.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>May their wives on them frown, but laugh and he down,</l>
                  <l>To any one elſe turn up Trump:</l>
                  <l>To mend the breed, as I think there is need,</l>
                  <l>Be rid like their men by the Rump.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And may theſe wiſe Sophies, pay again for their Trophies,</l>
                  <l>For I hope the Parliament means</l>
                  <l>(Now they ha' been at the coſts, to ſet up the poſts)</l>
                  <l>To make them pay well for the Chains.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:115486:9"/>
               <head>THE RUMP DOCK'T.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TIll it be underſtood</l>
                  <l>What's under <hi>Monck</hi>'s hood,</l>
                  <l>The City dare not ſhew his horns:</l>
                  <l>Till ten days be our,</l>
                  <l>The Speaker's ſick of the Gout,</l>
                  <l>And the <hi>Rump</hi> doth ſit upon thorns.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If <hi>Monck</hi> be turn'd Scot,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Rump</hi> goes to pot,</l>
                  <l>And the <hi>Good Old Cauſe</hi> will miſcarry;</l>
                  <l>Like coals out of embers,</l>
                  <l>Revive the Old Members;</l>
                  <l>Off goes the <hi>Rump,</hi> like <hi>Dick</hi> and <hi>Harry.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then in come the Lords,</l>
                  <l>Who drew Parliament ſwords,</l>
                  <l>With Robes lined through with Ermin:</l>
                  <l>But Peers without Kings</l>
                  <l>Are very uſeleſſe things,</l>
                  <l>And their Lordſhips counted but Vermin.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now <hi>Morley</hi> and <hi>Fagg</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>May be put in a bagg,</l>
                  <l>And that doughty man, Sir <hi>Arthur,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In deſpair for his Foil</l>
                  <l>With Alderman <hi>Hoyle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Will become a Knight of the Garter.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:115486:9"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>That Knave in Grain,</l>
                  <l>Sir <hi>Harry Vane,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His caſe than moſt men's is ſadder;</l>
                  <l>There is little hope</l>
                  <l>He can ſcape the Rope,</l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Rump</hi> turn'd him o're the Ladder</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That pretious Saint <hi>Scot</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Shall not be forgot,</l>
                  <l>According to his own deſires;</l>
                  <l>Inſtead of Neck-verſe,</l>
                  <l>He ſhall have writ on his Herſe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Here hangs one of the King's Triers.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thoſe nine ſons of <hi>Mars</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That whipt the <hi>Rump</hi>'s Arſe,</l>
                  <l>I mean the Commanders warlick;</l>
                  <l>If the <hi>Rump</hi> ſmell too ſtrong</l>
                  <l>With hanging too long,</l>
                  <l>Shall ſerve to ſtuffe it with Garlick.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That parcell of Man,</l>
                  <l>In length but a ſpan,</l>
                  <l>Whoſe wife's eggs always are addle;</l>
                  <l>Muſt quit the Life-guard,</l>
                  <l>As he did when skar'd</l>
                  <l>By <hi>Lambert</hi> out of the ſaddle.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:115486:10"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Lambert</hi> now may turn Floriſt,</l>
                  <l>Being come of the pooreſt</l>
                  <l>That ever did man of the Sword:</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Rump</hi> lett a fart</l>
                  <l>Which took away his heart,</l>
                  <l>And made him a Squire of a Lord.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His <hi>Cheſhire</hi> glory</l>
                  <l>Is a pittifull ſtory,</l>
                  <l>There the Saints triumph'd without Battle;</l>
                  <l>But now <hi>Monck</hi> and his Friers</l>
                  <l>Have driven him into the Briars,</l>
                  <l>As he did <hi>Booth</hi> and his Cattle.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For the reſt of the <hi>Rump,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Together in a lump,</l>
                  <l>'Tis too late to cry <hi>Peccavi;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Ye have ſinn'd all or moſt</l>
                  <l>Againſt the holy Ghoſt,</l>
                  <l>And therefore the Devill muſt have ye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But now valiant City,</l>
                  <l>Whether muſt thy Ditty</l>
                  <l>Be ſung in Verſe or in Proſe?</l>
                  <l>For till the <hi>Rump</hi> ſtunck</l>
                  <l>For fear of <hi>Monck,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thy <hi>Militia</hi> durſt not ſhew its noſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:115486:10"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Baſe Cowards and Knaves,</l>
                  <l>That firſt made us ſlaves,</l>
                  <l>Very Raſcals from the beginning;</l>
                  <l>Only unto <hi>Monck's</hi> Sword</l>
                  <l>The Nation muſt afford</l>
                  <l>The Honour of bringing the King in.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A NEW-YEARS-GIFT For the RUMP.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>YOu may have heard of the <hi>Politique Snout,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or a <hi>Tale of a Tub, with the bottom out,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But ſcarce of a <hi>Parliament</hi> in a <hi>ſhitten clout.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Twas <hi>Atkins</hi> firſt ſerv'd this <hi>Rump</hi> in with <hi>Muſtard,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Sawce</hi> was a compound of <hi>Courage,</hi> and <hi>Cuſtard;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Sr. Vane bleſs'd the Creature: Noll ſnufled, and Bluſter'd.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Right</hi> was as then, in <hi>Old Olivers Noſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But when the <hi>Devil,</hi> of that did <hi>diſpoſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It <hi>Deſcended from thence, to the Rump,</hi> in the Cloze.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Nor is it likely there to ſtay long,</l>
                  <l>The Retentive faculties being gone,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Juggle</hi> is <hi>stale,</hi> and <hi>Money</hi> there's none.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Secluded Members</hi> made a <hi>Trial</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="14" facs="tcp:115486:11"/>
                  <l>To <hi>Enter,</hi> but them the <hi>Rump</hi> did defy all,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>By the Ordinance of Self denial.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Our <hi>Politique Doctors</hi> do us Teach,</l>
                  <l>That a <hi>Blood-ſucking Red-coat's as good as a Leech,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>To Relieve the Head, if appli'd to the Breech.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But never was ſuch a <hi>worm</hi> as <hi>Vane;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When the <hi>State ſcour'd</hi> laſt, it <hi>voided</hi> him then,</l>
                  <l>Yet now he's <hi>crept</hi> into the <hi>Rump</hi> again.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ludlow</hi>'s <hi>Fart,</hi> was a <hi>Prophetique</hi> Trump:</l>
                  <l>(There never was any thing ſo Jump)</l>
                  <l>'Twas the very <hi>Type</hi> of a <hi>vote</hi> of this <hi>Rump.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They ſay, 'tis good Luck, when a <hi>Body riſes</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>With the Rump upward;</hi> but he that adviſes</l>
                  <l>To <hi>Live</hi> in that <hi>Poſture,</hi> is none of the wiſeſt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Reaſon</hi> is <hi>worſe,</hi> though the <hi>Rime</hi> be <hi>Untoward,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When things proceed with the <hi>wrong end Forward,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But they ſay there's ſad news to the <hi>Rump</hi> from the <hi>Nor'ward.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis a wonderfull thing the <hi>ſtrength</hi> of that Part,</l>
                  <l>At a <hi>Blaſt,</hi> it will take you a <hi>Team</hi> from a <hi>Cart;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>Blow</hi> a mans <hi>Head</hi> away with a <hi>Fart.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When our <hi>Brains</hi> are <hi>Sunck</hi> below the <hi>Middle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="15" facs="tcp:115486:11"/>
                  <l>And our <hi>Conſciences ſteer'd by the hey Down-Diddle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then things will go round without a Fiddle.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You may Order the <hi>City</hi> with a <hi>Hand-Granado,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or the <hi>Generall</hi> with a <hi>Baſtonado,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But no way for a <hi>Rump</hi> like a <hi>Carbonado,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>To make us as famous in <hi>Councill,</hi> as <hi>Wars,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Here's <hi>Lenthal, a Speaker for mine</hi> —</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Fleetwood is a man of Mars.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis pitty that <hi>Nedham</hi>'s fall'n into Diſgrace,</l>
                  <l>For he orders a <hi>Bumme</hi> with a marvellous Grace,</l>
                  <l>And ought to attend the <hi>Rump</hi> by his <hi>Place.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet this in ſpight of all Dyſaſters,</l>
                  <l>Although he hath <hi>Broken the Heads of his Maſters,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Tis ſtill his <hi>Profeſſion, to give 'em all Plaſters.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Let 'em cry down the Pope, till their Throats are ſore,</l>
                  <l>Their deſign was to bring him in at the Back-door:</l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Rump</hi> ha's a mind to the <hi>ſcarlet whore.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And this is a Truth at all hands confeſt,</l>
                  <l>However unskilfull in any of the reſt,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Rump ſpeaks the Language of the Beaſt.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They talk that <hi>Lambert</hi> is like to be <hi>try'd,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Treaſon,</hi> and <hi>Buggery</hi> beſide,</l>
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:115486:12"/>
                  <l>Becauſe that he did the <hi>Rump</hi> beſtride,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Rump</hi>'s an <hi>old ſtory</hi> if well underſtood,</l>
                  <l>'Tis a thing dreſs'd up in a Parliament's Hood,</l>
                  <l>And lik't, but the Tayl ſtands where the Head ſhould,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Twould make a man <hi>ſcratch where it does not itch,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To ſee forty fools heads in one politique Breech,</l>
                  <l>And that — <hi>Hugging the Nation as the Devill did the Witch,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>From rotten Members preſerve our Wives,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>From the mercy of a Rump,</hi> our Eſtates and our Lives:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For they muſt needs go whom the Devill drives,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>The Re-Reſurrection of the <hi>RUMP:</hi> Or, Rebellion and Tyranny reviv'd.</head>
               <head type="sub">The third Edition.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of the Blackſmith.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>IF none be offended with the Sent,</l>
                  <l>Though I foul my mouth, I'le be content,</l>
                  <l>To ſing of the <hi>Rump</hi> of a Parliament</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I have ſometimes fed on a Rump in Sowſe,</l>
                  <l>And a man may imagine the Rump of a Lowſe;</l>
                  <pb n="17" facs="tcp:115486:12"/>
                  <l>But till now was ne're heard of the <hi>Rump</hi> of a Houſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's a Rump of Beef, and the Rump of a Gooſe,</l>
                  <l>And a Rump whoſe Neck was hang'd in a Nooſe;</l>
                  <l>But ours is a <hi>Rump</hi> can play faſt and looſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A Rump had <hi>Jane Shore,</hi> and a Rump <hi>Meſſaleen,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And a Rump had <hi>Anthony</hi>'s reſolute Queen;</l>
                  <l>But ſuch a <hi>Rump</hi> as ours is, never was ſeen,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Two ſhort years together we Engliſh have ſcarce</l>
                  <l>Been rid of thy rampant Noſe (Old <hi>Mars</hi>)</l>
                  <l>But now thou haſt got a prodigious Arſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When the parts of the Body did all fall out,</l>
                  <l>Some Votes it is like did paſſe for the Snout;</l>
                  <l>But that the <hi>Rump</hi> ſhould be King was never a doubt,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A Cat has a Rump, and a Cat has nine Lives,</l>
                  <l>Yet when her Head's off, her Rump never ſtrives;</l>
                  <l>But our <hi>Rump</hi> from the grave hath made two Retrives</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That the Rump may all their enemies quail,</l>
                  <l>They'l borrow the Devil's Coat of Mail,</l>
                  <l>And all to defend their Eſtate in Tail,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But though their Scale now ſeem to be the Upper,</l>
                  <l>Ther's no need of the charge of a Thankſgiving Supper</l>
                  <l>For if they be the Rump, the Army's their Crupper,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:115486:13"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>There is a ſaying belongs to the Rump,</l>
                  <l>Which is good, although it be worn to the ſtump,</l>
                  <l>That on the Buttocks I'le give thee a Thump,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's a Proverb in which the Rump claims a part,</l>
                  <l>Which hath in it more of Senſe than of Art,</l>
                  <l>That for all you can do I care not a Fart,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Ther's another Proverb gives the Rump for his Creſt,</l>
                  <l>But Alderman <hi>Atkins</hi> made it a Jeſt,</l>
                  <l>That of all kind of Lucks, ſhitten Luck is the beſt,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There is another Proverb that never will fail,</l>
                  <l>That the good the Rump will do when they prevail,</l>
                  <l>Is to give us a flap with a Fox-tail,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There is a ſaying which is made by no fools,</l>
                  <l>I can never hear on't but my heart it cools,</l>
                  <l>That the Rump wil ſpend all we have in Cloſe-ſtools,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's an obſervation wiſe and deep,</l>
                  <l>Which without an Onyon will make me to weep,</l>
                  <l>That flies will blow maggots in the Rump of a ſheep,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And ſome that can ſee the Wood from the Trees,</l>
                  <l>Say, This ſanctifi'd Rump in time we may leeſe;</l>
                  <l>For the Cooks do challenge the Rumps for their fees,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When the Rump doth ſit we will make it our moan,</l>
                  <l>That a reaſon be 'nacted if there be not one,</l>
                  <pb n="19" facs="tcp:115486:13"/>
                  <l>Why a Fart hath a Toung and a Fyeſt hath none,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And whilſt within the Walls they lurk,</l>
                  <l>To ſatisfie us will be a good work,</l>
                  <l>Who hath moſt Religion, the Rump or the Turk,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A Rump's a Fag-end like the baulk of a Furrow,</l>
                  <l>And is to the whole like the Jayl to the Burrough;</l>
                  <l>'Tis the Bran that is left, when the meal is run thorough,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Conſider the World, the Heav'n is the head on't,</l>
                  <l>The Earth is the middle, and we men are fed on't,</l>
                  <l>But Hell is the Rump and no more can be ſaid on't,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <epigraph>
                  <q>
                     <hi>Flectere ſi nequeunt ſuperos Acheronta movebunt.</hi>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A VINDICATION Of the <hi>R<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>MP:</hi> or, the <hi>R<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>MP RE-ADVANC'D.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>Up Tails all.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>FUll many a Ballad hath been penn'd</l>
                  <l>and ſcoffing Poem writ</l>
                  <l>Againſt the <hi>RUMP;</hi> but I intend</l>
                  <l>to ſpeak in praiſe of it.</l>
                  <l>Come <hi>Jove</hi> and <hi>Apollo,</hi> come <hi>Venus</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:115486:14"/>
                  <l>And lend your aſſiſtance: to ſpeak of the <hi>A—</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Will require a prodigious wit.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's ſcarce a Lady to be found,</l>
                  <l>that loves either Pear or Plum</l>
                  <l>One half ſo well, if ſhe be ſound,</l>
                  <l>as tabering at her B—</l>
                  <l>It may be, you'l ſay, I'me wide of the caſe,</l>
                  <l>Since that Muſick's made in a diſtant place,</l>
                  <l>I anſwer, The breadth of your thum.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When Alderman <hi>Atkins</hi> did bemarre</l>
                  <l>his Hoſe through a panick fear,</l>
                  <l>And Captain <hi>Rea,</hi> that Man of Warr:</l>
                  <l>On! what a Hogo was there?</l>
                  <l>If you ask me, What praiſe is this? at a word,</l>
                  <l>The Captain ſo fenced himſelf by a T—</l>
                  <l>that his enemies could not come near.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There is not a Lawyer in Country or Town,</l>
                  <l>whoſe Rhetorick doth prevail</l>
                  <l>Although he hath purchas'd Fee-ſimple by th' Gown,</l>
                  <l>but loves to be dealing in Tail.</l>
                  <l>And I may well ſwear by <hi>Apollo</hi> or <hi>Mars,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That at a place called the <hi>Oven's Arſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oft-times I have drunken good Ale.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And when you are dallying with a young Maid,</l>
                  <l>would you not her buttocks bethump?</l>
                  <pb n="21" facs="tcp:115486:14"/>
                  <l>And I have been often well apaid</l>
                  <l>With a Gooſe both fat and plump:</l>
                  <l>The body being eaten, we ſtrive for the tail,</l>
                  <l>Each man with his Kan'kin of nappy brown Ale,</l>
                  <l>doth box it about for the <hi>RUMP.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Rump</hi> of a Cony I often have ſeen</l>
                  <l>moſt pitteouſly claw'd by a Ferret,</l>
                  <l>And a Capon's <hi>Rump</hi> is a bit for a Queen,</l>
                  <l>Although ſhe's a perſon of merit.</l>
                  <l>In preaching and praying who ſpends the whole day,</l>
                  <l>At night keeps a <hi>Rump</hi> wherewithall for to play,</l>
                  <l>be he never ſo full of the ſpirit.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I wonder who firſt call'd the Parliament <hi>Rump,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>ſome ſay, that it was <hi>Jack Hobby,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſome, fiery <hi>Pryn:</hi> good wits will jump;</l>
                  <l>now I write not this to bob ye,</l>
                  <l>But onely to tell ye, that good Mr. <hi>Pryn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For all he's cropt, yet he could not get in,</l>
                  <l>but was fain to remain in the <hi>Lobby.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The other day I was going in haſte,</l>
                  <l>(to think on't, it grieves my heart)</l>
                  <l>I ſaw a poor fellow all naked to the waſte,</l>
                  <l>and whipt at the Arſe of a Cart:</l>
                  <l>His <hi>Rump</hi> ('tis true) ſuffer'd the rout. But I would</l>
                  <l>Fain know who it was that durſt be ſo bold,</l>
                  <l>as to call Mr. Speaker Sir F—</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:115486:15"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>He might as well have ſtyled him <hi>Anus,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>ſince he was the mouth of the <hi>Rump,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As cunning a Fox as <hi>Rome</hi>'s <hi>Sejanus:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>but I do not love for to frump;</l>
                  <l>Or elſe I could tell ye, my friends, to an Ace,</l>
                  <l>What good can accrew to the Land by a Mace,</l>
                  <l>as long as the Knave's the greateſt Trump.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Our zealous ſticklers for Reformation</l>
                  <l>will edifie on the <hi>Rump</hi> of a ſiſter;</l>
                  <l>And it will never grow out of faſhion</l>
                  <l>to phyſick the Tail with a Gliſter.</l>
                  <l>But beware that <hi>Monck</hi> doth not come with a bitter</l>
                  <l>Purge to our <hi>Rump,</hi> which will make her beſhit her,</l>
                  <l>for ſhe hath already bepiſt her.</l>
               </lg>
               <trailer>RUMPATUR.</trailer>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:115486:15"/>
               <head>THE RUMP ULULANT, Or PENITENCE per FORCE; Being the Recantation of the old ruſty-roguy-rebellious-rampant, And now ruinous rotten-roſted RUMP.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of <hi>Gerrards Miſtreſſe.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>FArewell</l>
                  <l>Falſe Honours, and uſurped Power Farewell,</l>
                  <l>For the great Bell</l>
                  <l>Of Juſtice rings in our affrighted Ears.</l>
                  <l>The Gripes,</l>
                  <l>Of wounded Conſcience far exceed all Stripes,</l>
                  <l>Yet are ſmall Types,</l>
                  <l>Of thoſe ſharp Pains Rebellion juſtly fears,</l>
                  <l>See how,</l>
                  <l>Th' unmasked People hiſſe us out of Doors,</l>
                  <l>And call us Knaves,</l>
                  <l>Becauſe though we, Their Servants be,</l>
                  <l>We made them but our Slaves.</l>
                  <l>For ſince</l>
                  <l>We laid the Country waſt like ravenous Bores,</l>
                  <l>They ſeek our Bloods,</l>
                  <l>Becauſe we prize their Liberties,</l>
                  <l>But to devour their Goods.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:115486:16"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Our Hands</l>
                  <l>We dip'd in Royall Blood, to have his Lands</l>
                  <l>At our Commands,</l>
                  <l>And made three Kingdoms headleſs at one Blow,</l>
                  <l>The Strife</l>
                  <l>We caus'd was chiefly to cut off his Life,</l>
                  <l>With curſed Knife;</l>
                  <l>He that was Vertue's Friend, muſt be our Foe.</l>
                  <l>We made</l>
                  <l>Religion do our Drudgery to baſe Ends,</l>
                  <l>But now we find,</l>
                  <l>They that do ſow Pretences, mow</l>
                  <l>A Harveſt of the wind.</l>
                  <l>And now</l>
                  <l>When clamorous Vengeance Calling for Amends</l>
                  <l>Begins our Grief,</l>
                  <l>Our friend the Devil, with his Evil,</l>
                  <l>Can give us no Relief.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Go ſearch</l>
                  <l>All Lands beneath the Sun's Star-ſpangled Perch,</l>
                  <l>You'll find no Church</l>
                  <l>Like ours, whilſt Reverend <hi>BISHOPs</hi> held the Chayr.</l>
                  <l>But thoſe</l>
                  <l>We knew with our deſigns would never cloſe;</l>
                  <l>And therefore choſe</l>
                  <l>In their ſteads to ſet up <hi>Extempore</hi>-Prayer.</l>
                  <l>Poach'd eyes</l>
                  <l>And words twang'd through a whining Lecturer's Noſe,</l>
                  <l>Did fill our Purſes,</l>
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:115486:16"/>
                  <l>That many gave Rings, and better Things,</l>
                  <l>Which now give only Curſes.</l>
                  <l>And thus</l>
                  <l>Hell was our Text, though Heav'n were our Gloze,</l>
                  <l>And Will our Reaſon,</l>
                  <l>Religion we made free of <hi>Hocus</hi> trade,</l>
                  <l>And voted Loyalty Treaſon.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Since we</l>
                  <l>With wicked Arms have made the Croſier flee,</l>
                  <l>Errour is free,</l>
                  <l>To lay her Nets, to make weak Minds her Prize.</l>
                  <l>All Sects,</l>
                  <l>Schiſms, curſed Hereſies with ſtubborn Necks,</l>
                  <l>Corrupt our Texts,</l>
                  <l>And Crane up Scripture to maintain their Lyes,</l>
                  <l>You ſee</l>
                  <l>The Crop-ear'd Anabaptiſt ſowing Tares</l>
                  <l>In every Ground,</l>
                  <l>Though the Plagues of War, wherever they are</l>
                  <l>The Church and State Confound.</l>
                  <l>So do</l>
                  <l>The Roman Noſes vend their Popiſh Wares,</l>
                  <l>By Twylight ſtill;</l>
                  <l>And the Quaker half-mad, though he looks ſo ſad,</l>
                  <l>Grinds in the Jeſuites Mill.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Our Drums</l>
                  <l>Did drown your Proceſſe, and your Writs; our Plums,</l>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:115486:17"/>
                  <l>Bid kiſſe our Bums,</l>
                  <l>We ſent your Laws and Perſons to the <hi>Tower:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>From whence</l>
                  <l>To be deliver'd, 'Twas in vain to Fence</l>
                  <l>By talking Senſe;</l>
                  <l>No <hi>Habeas Corpus</hi> in the Court of Power.</l>
                  <l>The Gown</l>
                  <l>Did ſtoop his Reverend Velvet to a Crew</l>
                  <l>In ſhort Red Coats,</l>
                  <l>Who many a Day, Have made you pay,</l>
                  <l>For cutting your own Throats.</l>
                  <l>We rob'd</l>
                  <l>The Whole of Food to pamper up the Few,</l>
                  <l>Excis'd your Wares,</l>
                  <l>And tax'd you round, Six pence the Pound,</l>
                  <l>And maſſacred your Bears.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But now</l>
                  <l>Diſpair's black clowds do hang upon our Brow,</l>
                  <l>For all do Bow,</l>
                  <l>Their Hearts, to their true Shepheard, <hi>Charls</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And we</l>
                  <l>Their Wolfiſh Rulers now muſt Subjects be their King.</l>
                  <l>To Deſtiny,</l>
                  <l>And end our <hi>Juncto</hi> in a fatall String.</l>
                  <l>Then learn</l>
                  <l>All future Traytors by our Tragick Doom,</l>
                  <l>E're 'tis too late;</l>
                  <l>Leſt when you make, Kingdoms to ſhake,</l>
                  <l>You Copy out our Fate.</l>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:115486:17"/>
                  <l>We know</l>
                  <l>Our high affronts to Church and State make room</l>
                  <l>For Us in Hell;</l>
                  <l>But yet We'l hope, till the ſad Rope</l>
                  <l>Says, Bid the World <hi>Farewell.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <epigraph>
                  <q>
                     <hi>— Facit Indignatio Verſum.</hi>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>The BREECH Waſh'd, by a Friend to the <hi>RUMP.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>IN an humour of late I was,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Ycleped a <hi>dolefull dump.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thought I — We're at a fine paſſe;</l>
                  <l>Not a man ſtands up for the <hi>Rump,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But let it be laſh'd o're and o're,</l>
                  <l>While it lies like a ſenſeleſſe Fop —</l>
                  <l>'Twould make a <hi>Man</hi> a <hi>Whore,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To ſee a <hi>Tail tew'd like a Top.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Though a</hi> Rump <hi>be a dangerous bit,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And many a Knave runs mad on't,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Yet verily, as it may hit,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>An honeſt man may be glad on't.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>To abuſe a poor, <hi>Blind</hi> Creature —</l>
                  <l>I had like to have ſaid, and a <hi>Dumb;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But now it has gotten a <hi>Speaker,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>Say</hi> is the <hi>Mouth</hi> of the Bum.</l>
                  <l>When <hi>Beſſe</hi> rul'd the Land there was no man</l>
                  <pb n="28" facs="tcp:115486:18"/>
                  <l>Complain'd: and yet now they rail:</l>
                  <l>I beſeech you <hi>what differs a woman</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a thing that's all Toung and Tail?</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Though a</hi> Rump, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Charter</hi> we've ſworn to defend,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>propagate</hi> the Cauſe.</l>
                  <l>What call you thoſe of the <hi>Rump-end</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Fundamentall Laws?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Caſe</hi> is as clear as the day,</l>
                  <l>There had been no reformation,</l>
                  <l>If the <hi>Rump</hi> had not claw'd it away,</l>
                  <l>You had had no Propagation.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Though a</hi> Rump, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As a <hi>Body</hi>'s the better for a <hi>Purge,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Tho' the <hi>guts</hi> may be troubled with gripes:</l>
                  <l>So the <hi>Nation</hi> will mend with a <hi>ſcourge,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Tho'the <hi>Tail</hi> may be ſick of the <hi>ſtripes.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Ill <hi>humours</hi> to conveigh,</l>
                  <l>When the <hi>State</hi> hath taken a <hi>Looſneſſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(Who can hold what will away?)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The</hi> Rump <hi>muſt do the buis'neſſe.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tho' a</hi> Rump, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>bold Cavalier</hi> in the Field,</l>
                  <l>That laughs at your <hi>Sword</hi> and <hi>Gun-ſhot,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>An <hi>Ordinance</hi> makes him to <hi>yield,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And he's glad to turn Tail to <hi>Bumſhot.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Old Oliver</hi> was a Teazer,</l>
                  <l>And waged war with the <hi>Stump;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="29" facs="tcp:115486:18"/>
                  <l>But <hi>Alexander</hi> and <hi>Caeſar</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Did both <hi>ſubmit</hi> to the <hi>Rump.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tho' a</hi> Rump, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Let no man be further miſled</l>
                  <l>By an Error paſt debate.</l>
                  <l>For <hi>Sedgwick</hi> has prov'd it the <hi>Head,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As well of the <hi>Church</hi> as the <hi>State.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Honeſt Hugh,</hi> that ſtill turns up the <hi>Tippet,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When he kneels to <hi>Adminiſter;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Says — A <hi>Rump</hi> with <hi>Skippon's ſippits</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Is a Diſh for a <hi>Holy Siſter.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tho' a</hi> Rump, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Through <hi>pride</hi> of <hi>Fleſh</hi> or <hi>State,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Poor Souls are overthrown:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>How happy then is our Fate?</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We've a Rump to take us down.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In matters of <hi>Faith,</hi> 'tis true,</l>
                  <l>Some differings there may be;</l>
                  <l>But give the Saints their due</l>
                  <l>In the Rump they all agree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tho' a</hi> Rump, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis good at <hi>Bed</hi> and at <hi>Bord;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It gives us <hi>Pleaſure</hi> and <hi>Eaſe;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Will you have the reſt in a word?</l>
                  <l>'Tis good for the new Diſeaſe,</l>
                  <l>(The tumult of the Guts;)</l>
                  <l>'Tis a <hi>Recipe</hi> for the <hi>King's Evill.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="30" facs="tcp:115486:19"/>
                  <l>Waſh the Members as ſweet as Nuts,</l>
                  <l>And then throw them all to the Devill.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Though a</hi> Rump <hi>be a dangerous Bit,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And many a Knave runs mad on't;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Yet verily, as it may hit,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>An honeſt man may be glad on't.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>St. George <hi>for ENGLAND.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of <hi>Cook Lawrel.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>THe <hi>VVeſtminſter</hi>-Rump hath been little at eaſe,</l>
                  <l>Of which you have heard enough, one would think;</l>
                  <l>And therefore wee'l lay it aſide, if you pleaſe,</l>
                  <l>For the more we do ſtir in't the more it will ſtink.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Countie reſolves for a <hi>Parliament free,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Makes the Rump ſmell worſe than it did of late;</l>
                  <l>For now it runs down their heels, you may ſee.</l>
                  <l>You may call them our Privy-Members of State.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But why ſhould this Rump deal ſo roughly with <hi>Kent?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When <hi>England</hi> was conquer'd they were Scot-free;</l>
                  <l>Muſt they, for declaring, of all men be ſhent?</l>
                  <l>But Long-tail and Bob-tail can never agree.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:115486:19"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis much diſputed who Antichriſt is;</l>
                  <l>I think 'tis this Rump, nor am I in jeſt:</l>
                  <l>For indeed, although of the Number it miſſe,</l>
                  <l>Of this I am ſure, 't has the mark of the Beaſt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I cannot believe that our Generall <hi>Monck</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Intends to protect it, he's not ſuch a fool;</l>
                  <l>For if he were rightly inform'd how it ſtunck,</l>
                  <l>He never would joyn with ſuch Grooms of the Stool.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Though't be not whole Antichriſt, 'tis the worſt part,</l>
                  <l>By it both the Pope and the Turk are out-done;</l>
                  <l>If it be not the head, nor the feet, nor the heart,</l>
                  <l>'Tis the Rump of the Whore of <hi>Babylon.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So pocky, ſo ſtinking, ſo cheating to boot,</l>
                  <l>That he that has got but an eye or a noſe</l>
                  <l>Would never beſtride it. Then why ſhould you do't?</l>
                  <l>And make the poor Devill his ſtationſhip loſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If I might adviſe him, he ſhould not come near it,</l>
                  <l>The ſcent of that Houſe is naught for his Gout,</l>
                  <l>And for his Army too; he well may fear it,</l>
                  <l>'Tis enough to infect both his Horſe and his Foot.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Nor would I wiſh him to come to <hi>VVhite-hall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that hath been an unfortunate place;</l>
                  <l>From thence <hi>Noll</hi> was fetch'd, and <hi>Dick</hi> had his fall:</l>
                  <l>And <hi>George</hi> may take heed that it be not his caſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:115486:20"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>I remember the time when you fought for the King,</l>
                  <l>And the Cauſe was good, though you did not prevail.</l>
                  <l>O let not the Boys in the ſtreets now ſing,</l>
                  <l>He was once for the <hi>Head,</hi> but now for the <hi>Tail.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>George for England</hi> ſtrike up thy Drum,</l>
                  <l>And do thy devoir this Rump to deſtroy,</l>
                  <l>That noble King <hi>Charls</hi> the Second may come,</l>
                  <l>And our ſtreets may eccho with <hi>Vive le Roy.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And if <hi>He</hi> ſhall come by thy Valour and Might,</l>
                  <l>In that brave exploit thou'lt have more to brag on,</l>
                  <l>Than e're had Saint <hi>George</hi> that valiant Knight,</l>
                  <l>Who reſcued the Maid by killing the Dragon.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then lay by the thought of a <hi>Parliament free,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But firſt bring the <hi>King</hi> in, if you be wiſe;</l>
                  <l>For without <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Lords</hi> there none can be,</l>
                  <l>'Twill be but a Rump of a bigger ſiſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You know how to do it, &amp; need not much ſchooling,</l>
                  <l>All that you need to ſay, is, Let it be done.</l>
                  <l>Then why ſhould you ſtand delaying and fooling?</l>
                  <l>You fought for the Father, why not for the Son?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If you do not do't, much honour you'l loſe,</l>
                  <l>Which he and we mean you; for this we do know,</l>
                  <l>That in ſpight of the Rump and all other his foes,</l>
                  <l>He will be brought in whether you will or no</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:115486:20"/>
               <head>The Parliament-Complement, Or, The Re-admiſſion of the <hi>SECLUDED-MEMBERS</hi> to the Diſcharge of their long retarded <hi>TRUST.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>SInce ſixteen hundred forty and odd,</l>
                  <l>We have ſoundly been laſht with our own rod,</l>
                  <l>And have bow'd our ſelves down at a Tyrant's nod,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We have ſeen a new thing cal'd a Council of State,</l>
                  <l>Upheld by a power that's now out of date,</l>
                  <l>Put to th' queſtion, by'th Members of forty eight;</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We have ſeen what we hope, we ſhall ne're ſee agin,</l>
                  <l>Now <hi>Lambert</hi> and <hi>Desbrow</hi> are ſnar'd in the gin,</l>
                  <l>The Tail cunningly pieced unto the Skin,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A Sword that has frighted our Laws out of dore,</l>
                  <l>A Back-ſword I wot, that muſt cut ſo no more,</l>
                  <l>By th' Honour of <hi>Monck,</hi> now quitting that ſcore,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A Vote lately called, The judgment of th' houſe,</l>
                  <l>To be eſteem'd and reputed not worth a Louſe,</l>
                  <l>And the Grandee of <hi>Portſmouth</hi> made a fine Chouſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We have ſeen an Aſſeſſement, a Thing for Taxes,</l>
                  <l>Though the Common-wealth waine, the Private waxes:</l>
                  <pb n="34" facs="tcp:115486:21"/>
                  <l>Swords into Plowſhares, and ſuch bills to axes,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Another new ſtory of Qualification,</l>
                  <l>That belong'd to no honeſt man of the Nation,</l>
                  <l>Like the ill contriv'd Authors, quite of Faſhion.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Originall ſin, was damn'd by that Law,</l>
                  <l>The ſon of a Cavalier made a Jack-ſtraw,</l>
                  <l>To be chewed again by their rav'nous jaw,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>To fill up the Houſe, and to ſhuffle the deal,</l>
                  <l>New writs iſſued out, for their new Common-weal,</l>
                  <l>But it's not worth asking who is't payes the ſeal,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I wonder who payes the late Parliament Printers,</l>
                  <l>That place they may hold as many Summers as Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters,</l>
                  <l>And wiſh their Preſſes were broken in ſplinters.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A great many Traytors by them lately made,</l>
                  <l>Makes Treaſon be thought a common Trade,</l>
                  <l>Sir <hi>George Booth,</hi> and <hi>Jack Lambert,</hi> a while in the ſhade.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We ſhall now ſure give over that word Sequeſter,</l>
                  <l>Now the Tail is cured of their ranckling feſter,</l>
                  <l>The twentieth of <hi>April</hi> is much about Eaſter,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>How many Thanks of the Houſe have been idely ſpent</l>
                  <pb n="35" facs="tcp:115486:21"/>
                  <l>Upon People that ſtill have been male-content,</l>
                  <l>But they muſt faſt from thoſe dainties in this ſhriving Lent.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That honorable favour no more ſhall be given</l>
                  <l>To the factious merit of a party Hell-driven,</l>
                  <l>For now our twenty years odds will be even,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then room for our Priſoners detain'd in the Tower</l>
                  <l>And away with the new Lieutenant's power,</l>
                  <l>Who's minting the widdowed good old cauſe's Dower,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Sir <hi>George Booth,</hi> ſhall not think this is a hit of fate,</l>
                  <l>Nor excuſe his keeper, whoſe warrant's out of date,</l>
                  <l>We ſhall ſee them all cry <hi>Peccavi</hi> too late,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Eleven years miſchiefs, tumults and rage,</l>
                  <l>Are the onely memorialls of this Common-wealth's age,</l>
                  <l>And all to be thank't, be <hi>Hazelrigg</hi> the ſage,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Let our Liberty-keepers be chang'd to Reſtorer,</l>
                  <l>Let our Peace carry Truth and Duty before her,</l>
                  <l>He's a Fool and a Knave that elſe will adore her,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This <hi>Janus</hi>-like Freedom, though it pleaſe not us all</l>
                  <l>And averſly doth look on the Scepter and Ball</l>
                  <l>Will ſhut up its Temple at next Common-Hall,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:115486:22"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then let's pray to great <hi>Jove,</hi> that made <hi>Monck</hi> ſo kind</l>
                  <l>To our deſperate eſtate, to put him in mind,</l>
                  <l>With the reſt of our Worthies, of the <hi>Great Thing</hi> behind,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A Proper New BALLAD of the <hi>Devill's Arſe a Peak,</hi> or <hi>Satan's</hi> Beaſtly place. Or, in plain tearms, of the <hi>Posteriors</hi> and <hi>Fag-end</hi> of a <hi>LONG-PARLIAMENT.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To be ſaid or ſung very comfortably. <hi>To the Tune of, Cook Lawrell.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>O Fooliſh <hi>Britannicks,</hi> where are your hearts fled?</l>
                  <l>What Fiend doth the Nation bewitch,</l>
                  <l>That ſince you like Rogues cut off your own Head,</l>
                  <l>Your Noſes cloſe in with the Britch?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Britch! ſuch a bit, <hi>Noll's</hi> paunch could never brook,</l>
                  <l>For it put him ſtill to his dumps;</l>
                  <l>And though full-meals of Hell-broth he oft took,</l>
                  <l>Yet alwas he ſpew'd out the Rumps.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Till <hi>Lambert</hi> the Knave, and <hi>Fleetwood</hi> the Fool,</l>
                  <l>(Though <hi>Dick</hi> perſwaded them from it)</l>
                  <pb n="37" facs="tcp:115486:22"/>
                  <l>Did over-turn the Devill's Cloſe-ſtool,</l>
                  <l>And, like Dogs, return to their Vomit.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>No ſooner the Council-Table was ſpread</l>
                  <l>With many a vomited gull;</l>
                  <l>But the Army grew ſqueazy, and turned their head,</l>
                  <l>For they ſoon had their belly full.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Red-coats could never this Rumpling diſgeſt,</l>
                  <l>Till advis'd by old <hi>Nick</hi> and his train,</l>
                  <l>(Who good unwittingly oft may ſuggeſt)</l>
                  <l>They ſpew'd up their Vomit again.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Their Sirreverence was for a while out of ſight,</l>
                  <l>Till <hi>Whettam</hi> began to deplore 'em,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Arthur</hi> the Knight of the Spur, a bold Wight,</l>
                  <l>The Rump of a Rump did reſtore 'em.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then a pox light on the pittifull Rump,</l>
                  <l>That a third time above-board vapers,</l>
                  <l>Which old <hi>Nick</hi> blew out, but now turns up Trump,</l>
                  <l>As <hi>Joan</hi> farted in and out Tapers.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Houſe by this Legion was long time poſſeſt,</l>
                  <l>But at laſt they were caſt out of dore;</l>
                  <l>Yet finding it ſwept, return'd a new gueſt</l>
                  <l>Seven-times more a Fiend than before.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Away then ye pittifull Citizen-ſlaves,</l>
                  <l>Who let ſuch enormities paſſe;</l>
                  <pb n="38" facs="tcp:115486:23"/>
                  <l>Were you but true men, or nor errant knaves,</l>
                  <l>Fools durſt not you ride like an <hi>Aſs.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then dare to be honeſt, and beat up your Drum,</l>
                  <l>For when the Rogues hear of your power,</l>
                  <l>You'l ſmell what a ſcent proceeds from the Bum,</l>
                  <l>From <hi>White-hall</hi> at leaſt to the <hi>Tower.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>S'ſoot! what if theſe Arſe-worms with gifts of our gold</l>
                  <l>Great <hi>George</hi> to defend them ſhould move,</l>
                  <l>Our goods and our liberties then would be ſold,</l>
                  <l>And the Devill a <hi>Monck</hi> would he prove.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then pluck up your Spirits, and draw out your Swords,</l>
                  <l>'Tis force that muſt onely prevail,</l>
                  <l>We have long enough ſtood out in bare words,</l>
                  <l>Let's now make a Rod for their Tail.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Vive le Roy</hi> let's merrily ſing;</l>
                  <l>Can any man well in his wits</l>
                  <l>Think worſer of <hi>Charls</hi> our noble good KING,</l>
                  <l>Than thoſe who do govern by fits?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Search round the great City what ill you can ſee,</l>
                  <l>Which the raſcally <hi>Rump</hi> hath not done,</l>
                  <l>And then you will wiſh with the Nation and me,</l>
                  <l>That <hi>CHARLS</hi> had his Heritage won.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For Swearing, Sacriledge, Murther, and Lies,</l>
                  <l>KING-killing, Hypocriſie, Cheats;</l>
                  <pb n="39" facs="tcp:115486:23"/>
                  <l>They make no more of theſe ſins than of Flies,</l>
                  <l>HELL is almoſt out-damn'd by their Feats.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then fight ye like men for the good of the Nation,</l>
                  <l>As ye hope to be civilly drunck</l>
                  <l>On free-coſt at bleſſed <hi>CHARL'S</hi> Coronation,</l>
                  <l>Pray hard for the trueneſſe of <hi>Monck.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Heaven bleſs our good Soveraign, the beſt of all men,</l>
                  <l>Let the KING of our Hearts be Trump,</l>
                  <l>That peace and proſperity may come again,</l>
                  <l>Squire <hi>Dun</hi> and old <hi>Nick</hi> take the Rump.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then let the Knaves ſhuffle three Kingdoms a while,</l>
                  <l>Till each Curr at his fellow ſnarls;</l>
                  <l>Ere long they will cut, and after the broyl,</l>
                  <l>The dealing muſt fall to KING <hi>Charls.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This Flap with a Fox-tail ſhall have the ſame lot,</l>
                  <l>That unhorſt his Tumble-down Highneſſe;</l>
                  <l>For ſince the reſt of the Members are not,</l>
                  <l>The Rump muſt ſhortly have FINIS.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:115486:24"/>
               <head>Bum-Fodder, or Waſt-Paper, proper to wipe the <hi>Nation's RUMP</hi> with, or your own.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>FRee-quarter in the North is grown ſo ſcarce,</l>
                  <l>That <hi>Lambert</hi> with all his men of <hi>Mars</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Have ſubmitted to kiſs the Parliament's Arſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If this ſhould prove true (as we do ſuppoſe)</l>
                  <l>'Tis ſuch a wipe as the RUMP and all's foes,</l>
                  <l>Could never give to old <hi>Oliver</hi>'s Noſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's a Proverb come to my mind not unfit,</l>
                  <l>When the Head ſhall ſee the RUMP all be-ſhit,</l>
                  <l>Sure this muſt prove a moſt lucky hit,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's another Proverb which every Noddy</l>
                  <l>Will jeer the RUMp with, and cry Hoddy-doddy,</l>
                  <l>Here's a Parliament all Arſe and no Body,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis a likely matter the world will mend,</l>
                  <l>When ſo much blood and treaſure we ſpend,</l>
                  <l>And yet begin at the wrong end,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We have been round, and round about twirl'd,</l>
                  <l>And through much ſad confuſions hurl'd,</l>
                  <pb n="41" facs="tcp:115486:24"/>
                  <l>And now we art got into the Arſe of the world,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But 'tis not all this our courage will quail,</l>
                  <l>Or make the brave Sea-men to the RUMP ſtrike ſail;</l>
                  <l>If we can have no Head, we will have no Tail,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then let a <hi>Free Parliament</hi> be turn'd Trump,</l>
                  <l>And ne're think any longer the Nation to mump</l>
                  <l>VVith your pocky, perjur'd, damn'd old RUMP,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But what doth Rebell-<hi>Rump</hi> make here,</l>
                  <l>VVhen their proper place (as <hi>VVill. Pryn</hi> doth ſwear)</l>
                  <l>Is at the Devill's Arſe in <hi>Derbyſhire,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then thither let us ſend them a tilt,</l>
                  <l>For if they ſtay longer, they will us beguilt</l>
                  <l>VVith a Government that is looſe in the hilt,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You'l find it ſet down in <hi>Harrington</hi>'s Moddle,</l>
                  <l>VVhoſe brains a Common-wealth do ſo Coddle,</l>
                  <l>That t'as made a Rotation in his Noddle,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis a pittifull paſs you men of the Sword</l>
                  <l>Have brought your ſelves to, that the Rump's your Lord;</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Arſie-Verſie</hi> muſt be the word,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Our powder and ſhot you did freely ſpend,</l>
                  <l>That the Head you might from the Body rend,</l>
                  <l>And now you are at us with the But-end,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:115486:25"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Old <hi>Martin</hi> and <hi>Scot</hi> have ſtill ſuch an itch,</l>
                  <l>That they will with the <hi>Rump</hi> try t'other twitch,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Lenthal</hi> can greaſe a fat Sow in the Brich,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That's a thing that would pleaſe the Butchers and Cooks,</l>
                  <l>To ſee this ſtinking Rump quite off the hooks,</l>
                  <l>And Jack-daw go to pot with the Rooks,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This forward Sir <hi>John</hi> (who the Rump did ne're fail)</l>
                  <l>Againſt <hi>Charls Stewart</hi> in a ſpeech did rail,</l>
                  <l>But men ſay it was without head or tail,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Juſt ſuch is the Government we live under,</l>
                  <l>Of a Parliament thrice cut in ſunder;</l>
                  <l>And this hath made us the world's wonder,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Old <hi>Noll</hi> when we talk'd of <hi>Magna Charta,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Did propheſie well we ſhould all ſmart-a;</l>
                  <l>And now we have found his Rump's <hi>Magna Fart-a,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But I cann't think <hi>Monck</hi> (though a Soldier and Sloven)</l>
                  <l>To be kin to the Fiend whoſe feet are cloven,</l>
                  <l>Nor wil creep i'th' Rump's arſe to bake in their oven,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then ſince he is comming, e'ne let him come</l>
                  <l>From the North to the South with Sword &amp; Drum,</l>
                  <l>To beat up the quarters of this lewd Bum,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now of this Rump I'le ſay no more,</l>
                  <pb n="43" facs="tcp:115486:25"/>
                  <l>Nor had I begun, but upon this ſcore,</l>
                  <l>There was ſomething behind, which was not befor</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A HYMNE To the Gentle-Craft, Or, <hi>Hewſons</hi> Lamentation.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of the Blind Beggar.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>LIſten a while to what I ſhall ſay</l>
                  <l>Of a blind Cobler that's gone aſtray</l>
                  <l>Out of the Parliament's High way,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people pitty the blind.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His name you wot well is Sir <hi>John Hewſon</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whom I intend to ſet my Muſe on,</l>
                  <l>As great a Warriour as Sir <hi>Miles Lewſon,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He'd now give all the Shooes in his ſhop</l>
                  <l>The Parliaments fury for to ſtop,</l>
                  <l>Whip Cobler like any Town-top,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He hath been in many a bloody field</l>
                  <l>And a ſucceſsfull ſword did wield,</l>
                  <l>But now at laſt is forced to yield;</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Oliver</hi> made him a famous Lord</l>
                  <l>That he forgot his Cutting Bord,</l>
                  <pb n="44" facs="tcp:115486:26"/>
                  <l>But now his Thred's twiſted to a Cord,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Criſpin</hi> and he were neer of kin,</l>
                  <l>The gentle Craft have a noble Twin,</l>
                  <l>But he'd give Sir <hi>Hughs</hi> bones to ſave his skin,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Abroad and at home, he hath cut many a Hide,</l>
                  <l>A Dog and a Bell muſt now be his Guide,</l>
                  <l>They'l laſh him ſmartly on the blind ſide,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Of all his warlike valiant feats,</l>
                  <l>Of his Calves leather, and his Neats,</l>
                  <l>Let him ſpeak 'um himſelf when he repeats,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I'le only mention one exploit,</l>
                  <l>For which when he begs, Ile give him a Doit,</l>
                  <l>How he did the City vex and annoy't,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He marcht into <hi>London</hi> with Red-coat and Drum</l>
                  <l>During the time we had no Bum,</l>
                  <l>Being right for the Army as a Cow's Thum,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And there he did the Prentices meet,</l>
                  <l>Who jeered him as he went through the ſtreet,</l>
                  <l>But he did them very wel-favouredly greet,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Bears do agree with their own kind,</l>
                  <l>But he was of ſuch a cruell mind,</l>
                  <l>He kild his brother Cob. before he had din'd,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:115486:26"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>He ſtrutted then like a Crow in a Gutter,</l>
                  <l>That no body durſt once more Mutter,</l>
                  <l>The Capon-Citizens, gan to Flutter,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>After he had them thus defeated,</l>
                  <l>To his old quarters he retreated,</l>
                  <l>And was by <hi>Fleetwood</hi> nobly treated,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He is for this I hear Indited,</l>
                  <l>Though the Week before by them Invited,</l>
                  <l>But Wiſe Men ſay they had as good as Shited,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He cares not for the Seſſions a Lowſe,</l>
                  <l>They reach not a Peer of the other Houſe,</l>
                  <l>He's frighted to ſee that he is a Parliament Chouſe,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now he's gone the Lord knows whether,</l>
                  <l>He and this Winter go together,</l>
                  <l>If he be caught he will looſe his Leather,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>H'ad beſt get in ſome Countrey-Town,</l>
                  <l>And company keep with <hi>Desbrow</hi> the Clown,</l>
                  <l>You ſee how the World goes up and Down,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His Coach, and his Horſes, are gone to be Loſt,</l>
                  <l>He muſt vamp it and cart it and thank thee mine Hoſt,</l>
                  <l>Ther's no more to be ſaid of an old Toaſt,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Sing Hi Ho <hi>Hewſon,</hi> the State ne're went upright,</l>
                  <l>Since Coblers could Pray, Preach, Govern, and Fight,</l>
                  <pb n="46" facs="tcp:115486:27"/>
                  <l>We ſhall ſee what they'l do now you'r out of Sight.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Good people,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>Vanity of Vanities, or Sir <hi>Harry Vane</hi>'s Picture.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of <hi>Jews</hi> Corant.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>HAve you not ſeen a <hi>Barthol'mew</hi> Baby</l>
                  <l>A Pageant of policy as fine as may be,</l>
                  <l>That's gone to be Shown at the Mannor of <hi>Raby,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There was never ſuch a proſtitute Sight,</l>
                  <l>That e're profan'd this purer Light,</l>
                  <l>A <hi>Hocus Pocus</hi> jugling Knight,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He was taken for a Delphick <hi>Tripus,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Another doubt-reſolving <hi>Oedipus,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But the Parliament made him a very <hi>Quibus,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His cunning State-tricks and Oracles,</l>
                  <l>His lying wonders and Miracles,</l>
                  <l>Are turned into Parliament Shackles,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Goodly great Sir <hi>Oneſimus VANE,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The Annointed King of Saints not Reign?</l>
                  <l>I ſee all Godlineſſe is not Gain,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:115486:27"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>John</hi> a <hi>Leyden</hi> that <hi>Munſter's</hi> Jing,</l>
                  <l>Was a Fool and an Aſſe to this pretty Thing,</l>
                  <l>But the Parliament hated the name of a King,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This holy Saint hath pray'd till he wept,</l>
                  <l>Prophefied and Divin'd while he ſlept,</l>
                  <l>But fell in a T— when aſide he ſtept,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He ſate late in the Houſe ſo diſcontent,</l>
                  <l>With his Arms folded and his Brows bent,</l>
                  <l>Like <hi>Achitophel</hi> to the Parliament,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He durſt not ſpeak of a Concubine,</l>
                  <l>Nor gave more Counſell to any Deſign,</l>
                  <l>But was muſing on a Hempen Line,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He ſee Mr. <hi>Prin</hi> take a great deal of Pain,</l>
                  <l>To get in with the reſt as Members Again,</l>
                  <l>But they were Voted as uſe-leſſe as <hi>VANE,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They gave him a <hi>Congee</hi> with ſuch a Vote;</l>
                  <l>'Twas thought they had learned it by Rote,</l>
                  <l>Ever ſince he went down to <hi>Graves end</hi> by Bote,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For all his Ceremonious Cringing,</l>
                  <l>He ſhall undergo a notable Swindging,</l>
                  <l>There is now no more need of his Engine,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>VVhen firſt the Engliſh VVar began,</l>
                  <l>His Father was a Court <hi>Trepan,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="48" facs="tcp:115486:28"/>
                  <l>And 'roſe to be a Parliament Man,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So from the Father came unto the Son,</l>
                  <l>VVhom wo and miſ'ry now do wait upon,</l>
                  <l>For Counſelling Protector <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A <hi>Gemini</hi> they were, <hi>Pollux</hi> and <hi>Caſtor,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>One was a Teacher the other a Paſtor,</l>
                  <l>And both like R— betray'd their Maſter,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Devil ne're ſee ſuch two Sir <hi>Harry</hi>'s,</l>
                  <l>Such a peſt'lent pair nor neer nor far is,</l>
                  <l>No not at the Jeſuits <hi>Sorbon</hi> of <hi>Paris,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They talk't of his having a Cardinall's Hat,</l>
                  <l>They'd ſend him as ſoon an Old Nun's Twat,</l>
                  <l>For turning in pan there was ne're ſuch a Cat,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His dainty project of a Select Senate,</l>
                  <l>Is Damned for a blaſphemous Tenet,</l>
                  <l>T'was found in the budget, ('tis ſaid) of Monck <hi>Bennet,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Of this State and Kingdoms he is the Bane,</l>
                  <l>He ſhall have the reward of <hi>Judas</hi> and <hi>Cain,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And t'was he that overthrew <hi>Charls</hi> his VVain,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which no body,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Should he ſit where he did with his Miſchievous brain,</l>
                  <l>Or if any his Counſels behind do remain,</l>
                  <l>The houſe may be called the <hi>Labour in Vain,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>VVhich no body can deny.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:115486:28"/>
               <head>Chipps of the Old Block; or, <hi>Hercules</hi> cleanſing the <hi>Aegaean Stable.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>The Sword.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg n="1">
                  <head>I.</head>
                  <l>NOw you, by your good leave, Sirs,</l>
                  <l>Shall ſee the Rump can cleave, Sirs,</l>
                  <l>And what Chips from this treacherous Block wil</l>
                  <l>come you may conceive, Sirs.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="2">
                  <head>II.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Lenthal</hi>'s the firſt of the Lump ſure,</l>
                  <l>A Fart, and he may jump ſure;</l>
                  <l>For both do ſtink, and both we know, are Speakers</l>
                  <l>of the Rump ſure.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="3">
                  <head>III.</head>
                  <l>That Mine of fraud Sir <hi>Artur,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His Soul for Lands will barter;</l>
                  <l>And if you ride to Hell in a Wayn, he's fit to make</l>
                  <l>your Carter.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="4">
                  <head>IV.</head>
                  <l>Sir <hi>Harry Vane,</hi> God bleſſe us,</l>
                  <l>To Popery he would preſſe us;</l>
                  <l>And for the Devill's dinner he, the <hi>Roman</hi> way would dreſſe us.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="5">
                  <head>V.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Harry Martin</hi> never miſt-a,</l>
                  <l>To love the wanton twiſt-a;</l>
                  <pb n="50" facs="tcp:115486:29"/>
                  <l>And luſtfull Aretine's bawdy Leaves are his Evangeliſt-a.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="6">
                  <head>VI.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Harry Nevill</hi>'s no VVigeon,</l>
                  <l>His practiſe truly Stygian</l>
                  <l>Makes it a Maſter-piece of wit to be of no Religion.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="7">
                  <head>VII.</head>
                  <l>But my good Lord <hi>Glyn</hi> Man,</l>
                  <l>Pride is a deadly ſinne Man,</l>
                  <l>Cots pluttera nails few Traitors be like you of all your kin Man.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="8">
                  <head>VIII.</head>
                  <l>If <hi>Saint-John</hi> be a Saint Sir,</l>
                  <l>He hath a Deviliſh Taynt Sir,</l>
                  <l>VVhile <hi>Straffords</hi> blood in Heavens High Court of Juſtice makes complaint Sir.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="9">
                  <head>IX.</head>
                  <l>Doctor <hi>Palmer</hi>'s all day ſleeping,</l>
                  <l>And into his Heart ne're peeping,</l>
                  <l>Tis ill he that neglects his own, ſhould have All-ſouls in keeping.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="10">
                  <head>X</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Will. Bruerton</hi>'s a ſinner,</l>
                  <l>And, <hi>Croyden</hi> knowes, a Winner,</l>
                  <l>But O take heed, leſt he do eat the Rump all at one Dinner.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="11">
                  <head>XI.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Andrews</hi> is a Miſer,</l>
                  <l>Of Coblers no deſpiſer,</l>
                  <pb n="51" facs="tcp:115486:29"/>
                  <l>And could they vamp him a new head, perhaps he would be wiſer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="12">
                  <head>XII.</head>
                  <l>* But Baron <hi>VVild</hi> come out here,</l>
                  <l>Shew your Ferret face and Snout here,</l>
                  <l>For you being both a Fool and Knave are a Monſter in the Rout here.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="13">
                  <head>XIII.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Nich. Lechmere</hi> Loyalty needs ſtill,</l>
                  <l>And on Weather-cocks he feeds ſtill,</l>
                  <l>If Heathen, Turk, or Jew ſhould come, ſo he would change his Creed ſtill.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="14">
                  <head>XIIII.</head>
                  <l>There's half-witted <hi>VVill. Say</hi> too,</l>
                  <l>A right fool in the Play too,</l>
                  <l>That would make a perfect Aſſe, if he could learn to Bray too.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="15">
                  <head>XV.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cornelius</hi> thou wert a Link-boy,</l>
                  <l>And born tis like, in a Sink boy,</l>
                  <l>I'de tell thy Knavery to the World, but thy Pitch ſticks in my ink, Boy.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="16">
                  <head>XVI.</head>
                  <l>Baron <hi>Hill</hi> was but a Valley,</l>
                  <l>And born ſcarce to an Alley,</l>
                  <l>But now is Lord of <hi>Taunton-Deane</hi> and thouſands he can Ralley.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="17">
                  <head>XVII.</head>
                  <l>But if you ask the Nation,</l>
                  <l>Whence came his Elevation,</l>
                  <pb n="52" facs="tcp:115486:30"/>
                  <l>They'l ſay he was not rais'd by God, but by our inundation.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="18">
                  <head>XVIII.</head>
                  <l>Lord <hi>Fines</hi> he will not Mall men,</l>
                  <l>For he likes not Death of all men,</l>
                  <l>And his Heart doth go to Pit to Pat, when to Battle he ſhould call men.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="19">
                  <head>XIX.</head>
                  <l>Perfidious <hi>VVhitlock</hi> Ever,</l>
                  <l>Hath miſchief under's Beaver,</l>
                  <l>And for his ends will put the World into a burning Feavour.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="20">
                  <head>XX.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Aſhely Cowper</hi> knew a Reaſon,</l>
                  <l>That Treachery was in Seaſon,</l>
                  <l>When at the firſt he turn'd his coat from Loyalty to Treaſon.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="21">
                  <head>XXI.</head>
                  <l>And gouty Maſter <hi>VVallop,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now thinks he hath the Ballop,</l>
                  <l>But though he trotted to the Rump, hee'l run away a Gallop.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="22">
                  <head>XXII.</head>
                  <l>There's <hi>Carew Rawleigh</hi> by him,</l>
                  <l>All good Men do defie him,</l>
                  <l>And they that think him not a Knave, I wiſh they would but try him.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="23">
                  <head>XXIII.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Luke Robinſon</hi> that Clownado,</l>
                  <l>Though his heart be a Granado,</l>
                  <pb n="53" facs="tcp:115486:30"/>
                  <l>Yet a High-Shooe with his hands in's Poke, is his moſt perfect ſhadow.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="24">
                  <head>XXIIII.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Saloway</hi> with Tobacco,</l>
                  <l>Inſpired, turn'd State Quacko;</l>
                  <l>And got more by his feigned zeal, then by his what de'e Lack ho.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="25">
                  <head>XXV.</head>
                  <l>But <hi>VViddrington</hi> how came you there?</l>
                  <l>A wiſe man and a true there!</l>
                  <l>You are an <hi>Athanaſius</hi> among a Knaviſh Crew there.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="26">
                  <head>XXVI.</head>
                  <l>But <hi>Liſle</hi> is half forgotten,</l>
                  <l>Who oft is over ſhotten,</l>
                  <l>For juſt like Harp and Gridiron, his Brains with Law do Cotten.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="27">
                  <head>XXVII.</head>
                  <l>Lord <hi>Monſon</hi>'s next the Bencher,</l>
                  <l>Who waited with a Trencher,</l>
                  <l>How his tayl is jeck'd at home and abroad, for he's a feeble Wencher.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="28">
                  <head>XXVIII.</head>
                  <l>We hear from Sir <hi>John Lenthal,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Though this gouty Lord hath ſpent all,</l>
                  <l>His Rump's plac'd wrong, but 'tis his face, that is right fundamentall.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="29">
                  <head>XXIX.</head>
                  <l>What Knaves are more to be vext Sirs,</l>
                  <l>You'l here when I ſing next Sirs,</l>
                  <pb n="54" facs="tcp:115486:31"/>
                  <l>For now my Muſe is tir'd with this abominable Text Sirs.</l>
               </lg>
               <epigraph>
                  <q>
                     <hi>Ridentem dicere verum, Quid vetat?</hi>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A PSALM ſung by the <hi>People,</hi> before the Bone-Fires, made in and about the City of <hi>London,</hi> on the 11th. of <hi>February.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>Vp tails all.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>COme let's take the <hi>Rump</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And waſh it at the Pump,</l>
                  <l>For tis now in a ſhitten caſe:</l>
                  <l>Nay if it hang an Arſe,</l>
                  <l>Wee'l pluck it down the ſtares,</l>
                  <l>And roaſt it at Hell for its greaſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Let the Divell be the Cook</l>
                  <l>And the roaſt overlook,</l>
                  <l>And lick his own fingers apace;</l>
                  <l>For that may be born,</l>
                  <l>(If he take it not in ſcorn</l>
                  <l>To lick ſuch a privy place.)</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Though we are bereft</l>
                  <l>Of our Arms, Spits are left,</l>
                  <pb n="55" facs="tcp:115486:31"/>
                  <l>Whereon the <hi>Rump</hi> we will roaſt;</l>
                  <l>Wee'l prick it in the Tail,</l>
                  <l>And baſt it with a Flayl,</l>
                  <l>Till it ſtink like a Cole-burnt Toaſt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>It hath lain long in brine,</l>
                  <l>Made by the people's eyne,</l>
                  <l>So 'tis ſalt through unſavory meat;</l>
                  <l>Wee'l draw it round about</l>
                  <l>With Welſh Parſley, and no doubt</l>
                  <l>It will choak <hi>Pluto</hi>'s great Dog to eat.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>VVe will not be mockt</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Rump</hi> hath been dock't,</l>
                  <l>And if our skill doth not fail;</l>
                  <l>To fear it is good,</l>
                  <l>Or elſe all the blood</l>
                  <l>In the body, will leak out at the Tail.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then down in your Ire,</l>
                  <l>VVith this <hi>Rump</hi> to the fire,</l>
                  <l>Get <hi>Harrington</hi>'s <hi>Rota</hi> to turn it;</l>
                  <l>If paper be lack't,</l>
                  <l>The Aſſeſsment Act</l>
                  <l>You may ſtick upon't leſt ye burn it.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But ſee there my Maſters</l>
                  <l>It riſes in bliſters,</l>
                  <l>And looks very big on the matter;</l>
                  <l>Like a roaſting Pigs eare</l>
                  <pb n="56" facs="tcp:115486:32"/>
                  <l>It ſings, do ye hear?</l>
                  <l>'Tis enough, come quickly the Platter.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Lay Trenchers and Cloth</l>
                  <l>And away bring the Broth,</l>
                  <l>Did the Divel o'th Fag end make none;</l>
                  <l>But hold by your leave</l>
                  <l>Napkins we muſt have</l>
                  <l>To wipe our mouths when we have done.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come Ladies pray where?</l>
                  <l>VVill you none of our chear?</l>
                  <l>Are ye of ſuch a ſqueamiſh nature?</l>
                  <l>Pray what is your reaſon,</l>
                  <l>Are Rumps out of ſeaſon?</l>
                  <l>But 'tis an abuſe to the Creature.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come wee'l fall on</l>
                  <l>Pray cut me a bone</l>
                  <l>The Meat may be healthfull and ſound;</l>
                  <l>Fogh! come let us bury't</l>
                  <l>To th' hole we muſt carry't,</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Rump</hi> it ſtinks above ground.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This fire wee'l ſtile</l>
                  <l>The Funerall pile,</l>
                  <l>The Grave ſhall be under the Gallowes;</l>
                  <l>The Vane ſhall be th' ſcull,</l>
                  <l>Of ſome Trayterous-Fool,</l>
                  <l>And the Epitaph ſhall be as follows.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:115486:32"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Underneath theſe Stones</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>A Rump-Corporate's bones,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Are laid full low in a ſink,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And we do implore yee</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Let them reſt, for the more yee</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Do ſtir them, the more they will stink.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>LONDON'S true Character.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>YOu Coward-hearted <hi>Citizens,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>what is your Damn'd pretence,</l>
                  <l>To keep your ſelves within your Beds,</l>
                  <l>and not Fight for your Prince?</l>
                  <l>Whoſe Majeſty ſhould you behold,</l>
                  <l>your ſhames would breed your woe;</l>
                  <l>And then (like Fools) you will cry out,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There's ſome of you, whoſe <hi>Biſhops Lands</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>do ſo much clogg your heels,</l>
                  <l>That now you cannot ſtirr, where as</l>
                  <l>elſe, you would Run on Wheels:</l>
                  <l>But yet I hope a time will come,</l>
                  <l>when you ſhall be made know,</l>
                  <pb n="58" facs="tcp:115486:33"/>
                  <l>And told to your faces, that you are</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But yet for one moſt Reverend Act,</l>
                  <l>you are to be commended;</l>
                  <l>That through your Rams-head zeal you have</l>
                  <l>your Brother <hi>RUMP</hi> befriended,</l>
                  <l>To ſeat them in the <hi>Parliament</hi>-houſe,</l>
                  <l>their Wiſedomes forth to ſhow;</l>
                  <l>But they (and you) are all a-like,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet I adviſe you, ſet this <hi>Rump</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>in Salt, for fear of Stinking;</l>
                  <l>'Twill fall unto the Devil's ſhare,</l>
                  <l>becauſe 'tis his by drinking:</l>
                  <l>In ſpight of all their <hi>Acts,</hi> and <hi>Laws,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Hee'l carry them down below;</l>
                  <l>Then <hi>Hell,</hi> and <hi>City,</hi> like to like,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I doubt, your <hi>Lambert</hi> is undone,</l>
                  <l>and now he may go Preach;</l>
                  <l>For 'tis the <hi>Engliſh all-a-moad,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>for every Rogue to Teach:</l>
                  <l>Hee'l Noſe it bravely in a Tub,</l>
                  <l>to let the <hi>City</hi> know</l>
                  <l>That they'l be Damn'd, unleſs they Dipp,</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="59" facs="tcp:115486:33"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>But where's your mighty <hi>Fleetwood</hi> now,</l>
                  <l>his Honour's worn to the Stump;</l>
                  <l>Hee'l ſerve Ambaſſador to <hi>Hell,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>to make way for the <hi>Rump.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And thus <hi>King-killers,</hi> one by one</l>
                  <l>will to the Devill go,</l>
                  <l>Upon the City Aſſes backs, like</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now Cow-hearts, look to your Shops</l>
                  <l>the <hi>Red-Coats</hi> will you fright;</l>
                  <l>And Plunder you, becauſe they know</l>
                  <l>your Horns hang in your light:</l>
                  <l>No matter, for You have been the cauſe</l>
                  <l>of all the Kingdoms woe,</l>
                  <l>And do deſerve ſtill to be call'd</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But if that you would honeſt grow,</l>
                  <l>and doe a glorious thing;</l>
                  <l>Which is, to Rowſe and take your Armes.</l>
                  <l>and Fight for <hi>Charls</hi> your King:</l>
                  <l>Which Act your Credits will regain,</l>
                  <l>and all the World ſhall know</l>
                  <l>That you no more, ſhall then be call'd</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cuckolds all-a-Row.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="60" facs="tcp:115486:34"/>
               <head>A Diſplay of the Headpiece and Codpiece Valour, of the moſt Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nowned, Colonel <hi>Robert Jermy,</hi> late of <hi>Bafield</hi> in the County of <hi>Norfolk,</hi> Eſq; with his ſon Captain <hi>Toll</hi> by his ſide; now on their way for <hi>New-England.</hi> Or, the lively deſcription of a dead-hearted fellow.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of a <hi>Turd,</hi> or the <hi>Black-ſmith.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>DId you ne're hear of the Baby of <hi>Mars,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That charg'd <hi>Tom Fox</hi>'s wife with a Tars,</l>
                  <l>For his valour lies all in his Arſe,</l>
                  <l>Which needs muſt be very ſtrong.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A ſanctifi'd Colonel in beaten Buff,</l>
                  <l>With a Scarlet Jump that's <note n="a" place="bottom">Cudgell'd by <hi>Mr. Armiger</hi> at <hi>Wells</hi> in <hi>Norfolk, Novemb.</hi> 4. 1654.</note> Cudgel-proof;</l>
                  <l>And his ſon <note n="b" place="bottom">Ran away ſix miles at <hi>Crowland</hi> Siege, and ne're lookt behind him.</note> 
                     <hi>Crowland</hi> Coward of the ſelf-ſame ſtuff,</l>
                  <l>Who got the wench big with young. <hi>Probatum eſt.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He's a journey-man Souldier to the State's Army,</l>
                  <l>And 'tis in his terms, When you fight you muſt ſpare me:</l>
                  <l>So runs the Commiſſion of Colonel <hi>Jermy,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>If I be informed true.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:115486:34"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Upon a mock-Larm he's ſure in the Van,</l>
                  <l>Where he takes none, and does no more hurt than he can.</l>
                  <l>He's a pittifull Souldier, though a cruell man,</l>
                  <l>Let's give the Devill his due.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>To ſacrifice to his fears and his pride,</l>
                  <l>He caus'd a <note n="c" place="bottom">He cauſed Parſon <hi>Cooper</hi> to be hang'd by Iudge <hi>Iermy,</hi> for fear he ſhould beat him.</note> Church-Champion be murder'd and try'd</l>
                  <l>By the Judge of his name, and the Rope on his ſide;</l>
                  <l>'Tis pitty they ever were parted.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet you cannot but ſay, 'twas very well meant,</l>
                  <l>When he went to the Houſe of Parliament,</l>
                  <l>In love to his Country before he was ſent,</l>
                  <l>In a Coach, when he might have been Carted.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You muſt always take the good-will for the deed,</l>
                  <l>Though at <note n="d" place="bottom">He corrupted twenty free Burghers at <hi>Riſen,</hi> to give their <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>otes for him in the laſt Election for Parliament.</note> 
                     <hi>Riſen</hi> he had not the luck to ſpeed;</l>
                  <l>Yet ſome other place may have very great need,</l>
                  <l>If the Devill releaſe but his hire.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So dear was his love that he <note n="e" place="bottom">He hired 100 men to come with him from <hi>Lyn</hi> with ſwords and guns, for fear Mr. <hi>Howard</hi> and his two men ſhould beat him.</note> purchas'd a throng</l>
                  <l>Of Sea-men, in Lice and Lungs very ſtrong.</l>
                  <l>Sure he will be ſome body ere it be long,</l>
                  <l>If he be not laid in the mire.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:115486:35"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>How the Sailers did hollow and throw up their hats,</l>
                  <l>And the men with wide mouthes that us'd to cry Sprats;</l>
                  <l>But the brave ſpark of <hi>Arundel</hi> made them look like drown'd Rats,</l>
                  <l>When he <note n="f" place="bottom">Mr. <hi>Howard</hi> gave him a box on the ear with the back of his hand, and he fell to the ground with fear.</note> humbled <hi>Tom Toll</hi> for his ſin.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That high-born Hero had cudgel'd their Swords,</l>
                  <l>Had they not almoſt expir'd at his words;</l>
                  <l>But the whole deſigne was not worth two half-turds,</l>
                  <l>Though you throw the <note n="g" place="bottom">Juſtice <hi>Cremar,</hi> Justice <hi>Peddar,</hi> and Juſtice <hi>Life.</hi>
                     </note> three Juſtices in.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>In his laſt good ſervice he <note n="h" place="bottom">He took the City of <hi>Norwich</hi> when the Gates were open, and no oppoſition.</note> took the City,</l>
                  <l>By an order from the miſtaken Committee,</l>
                  <l>Where he ſcap'd a ſcowring, the more was the pitty;</l>
                  <l>For 'twas foul when you've ſaid what you can.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He march'd into the Gates with an hundred more,</l>
                  <l>O brave! he ne're did the like before;</l>
                  <l>For he us'd to ſneak in at the <note n="i" place="bottom">Mrs. <hi>Foxe</hi>'s back dore.</note> back dore,</l>
                  <l>As becomes a right modeſt man.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When they entred the Town they beleagur'd the Mayor,</l>
                  <l>And with wonderfull courage they ſtormed the Chair;</l>
                  <pb n="63" facs="tcp:115486:35"/>
                  <l>But they ſoon were all foul, and ran very fair,</l>
                  <l>As if they'd been bred for the Courſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For the <note n="k" place="bottom">The Bells were rung backward, which alarm'd the City, who came in and had beat him, if he had not run away upon the noiſe of it.</note> Bells were rung backward, as he ſays his prayers,</l>
                  <l>And his head went forward with his haſte down the ſtairs,</l>
                  <l>Like a man of diſpatch in the State-affairs,</l>
                  <l>Thank Fortune it was no worſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis much to be wonder'd he ſhould leave the Rump,</l>
                  <l>Though his love to that end has receiv'd a Law-frump,</l>
                  <l>But that is his god what ever is Trump;</l>
                  <l>Yet his ſpirit now was blind.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Had the Rump but once fizl'd, 'twas the ſtrongeſt ſide,</l>
                  <l>But a Fart has ſo routed his Troop in their pride,</l>
                  <l>Though infallible <note n="l" place="bottom">
                        <hi>Iermy</hi>'s Chaplain, that prays, and ſwears, and fights, and lies for him in ordinary.</note> 
                     <hi>Butler</hi> was his guide,</l>
                  <l>That they are both blown down the wind.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet that would be thought a true <note n="m" place="bottom">Let us ſhew our ſelves true Engliſh-men, is his uſuall ſaying,</note> Engliſh-man,</l>
                  <l>Let him make true Latine if he can;</l>
                  <l>Yet learned mens lives this Raſcall will ſcan,</l>
                  <l>And when he has done it deny it.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="64" facs="tcp:115486:36"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>This is <hi>Jermy</hi>'s Forlorn when brave <hi>Jacks</hi> appear.</l>
                  <l>He has little of wit, and leſſe of fear,</l>
                  <l>And ſwears for his Colonel by the year;</l>
                  <l>And when he is in, he will ply it.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When the Nation was Jaded with a <note n="m" place="bottom">He that dranck ſo much Aſſes milk, as, without the Parliament's mercy, he is like to be a fool for ever.</note> Quaker,</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Jippoe</hi> for-ſooth was a great undertaker,</l>
                  <l>And amongſt other Trades a Juſtice-maker,</l>
                  <l>
                     <note n="n" place="bottom">Two <hi>Iuſtices</hi> in <hi>Norfolk.</hi>
                     </note>
                     <hi>Brewer, Tirrell,</hi> and Gaffer <hi>Life.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Were made and created by his ſtinking breath,</l>
                  <l>To ſit on the Bench upon Life and Death.</l>
                  <l>We'd as good have had a turd in our teeth,</l>
                  <l>VVithout any further ſtrife.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I thought this Colonel would fail,</l>
                  <l>VVhen he was upon his Codpiece-bail,</l>
                  <l>He got ſuch a flap with a Fox tail,</l>
                  <l>As more at large in your <note n="o" place="bottom">Master <hi>Armiger</hi> hath the exemplification of a Verdict in a Box, wherein <hi>Iermy</hi>'s baudery with <hi>Foxe's</hi> wife, is ſet forth.</note> Box, Sir.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But now if we may believe common fame.</l>
                  <l>At preſent they ſay he's fled for the ſame,</l>
                  <l>How poorly this fellow has plaid his game!</l>
                  <l>But let him not ſcape without knocks, Sir.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet he is ſuch a Coward that I dare ſay,</l>
                  <pb n="65" facs="tcp:115486:36"/>
                  <l>He neither dares fight, nor yet run away,</l>
                  <l>And yet he'd be glad to ſtand at a ſtay,</l>
                  <l>If he might but have his <hi>Quietus.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For tell him his baſeneſſe but once to his face</l>
                  <l>Y' are ſure enough he dies on the place,</l>
                  <l>If he hangs not himſelfe upon this diſgrace,</l>
                  <l>'Tis One to a Thouſand hee'l beat us.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A New BALLAD,</head>
               <opener>To an Old Tune, <hi>Tom of Bedlam.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>MAke room for an <hi>honeſt Red-coat,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(And that you'l ſay's a wonder)</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Gun,</hi> and the <hi>Blade,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Are his <hi>Tools,</hi> — and his <hi>Trade</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Is for <hi>Pay,</hi> to <hi>Kill,</hi> and <hi>Plunder.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away with the Laws,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And the</hi> Good old Cauſe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne'r talk o' the</hi> Rump, <hi>or the</hi> Charter,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>'Tis the Caſh does the Feat,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>All the</hi> reſt's <hi>but a</hi> Cheat,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Without</hi> That <hi>there's no</hi> Faith, <hi>nor</hi> Quarter.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis the Mark of our Coin, GOD WITH US,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And the Grace of the Lord goes along with't,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When the <hi>Georges</hi> are flown,</l>
                  <l>Then the <hi>Cauſe goes down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="66" facs="tcp:115486:37"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For the Lord is departed from it.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For <hi>Rome,</hi> or for <hi>Geneva,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Table,</hi> or the <hi>Altar,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This ſpawn of a Vote,</l>
                  <l>He cares not a Groat —</l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Pence,</hi> hee's your Dog in a Halter.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Tho' the Name of <hi>King,</hi> or <hi>Biſhop,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>to Noſtrils pure may be <hi>Loathſom,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet many there are,</l>
                  <l>That agree with the <hi>Mayor,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That their <hi>Lands are wondrous toothſom.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When our Maſters are Poor, we leave 'em,</l>
                  <l>'Tis the <hi>Golden Calf</hi> we bow to:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We kill, and we ſlay,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Not for Conſcience, but Pay;</l>
                  <l>Give us That, wee'l fight for you too.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Twas <hi>That</hi> firſt turn'd the <hi>King</hi> out;</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Lords,</hi> next: then, the <hi>Commons:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Twas that kept up <hi>Noll,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Till the Devil fetch'd his Soul;</l>
                  <l>And then it ſet the <hi>Bum</hi> on's.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="67" facs="tcp:115486:37"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Drunken Dick,</hi> was a <hi>Lame Protector,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>Fleetwood</hi> a <hi>Backſlider:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe we ſerv'd as the reſt,</l>
                  <l>But the City's the Beaſt</l>
                  <l>That will never caſt her Rider.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When the <hi>Mayor</hi> holds the <hi>Stirrop,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And the <hi>Shreeves</hi> cry, <hi>God ſave your Honours:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then, 'tis but a Jump,</l>
                  <l>And up goes the Rump,</l>
                  <l>That will ſpur to the Devil upon us.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now for a fling at your <hi>Thimbles,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Your <hi>Bodkins, Rings,</hi> and <hi>Whiſtles,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In truck for your Toyes,</l>
                  <l>Wee'l fit you with Boys:</l>
                  <l>('Tis the Doctrine of <note n="*" place="bottom">To the Butchers Wife.</note> 
                     <hi>Hugh's Epiſtles.</hi>)</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When your <hi>Plate</hi> is gone, and your <hi>Jewels,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>You muſt be next entreated,</l>
                  <l>To part with your <hi>Bags,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſtrip you to <hi>Rags,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yet not think y' are cheated.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="68" facs="tcp:115486:38"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>The truth is, the <hi>Town</hi> deſerves it;</l>
                  <l>'Tis a <hi>Brainleſs, Heartleſs Monſter:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>At a <hi>Clubb</hi> they may <hi>Bawl,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or <hi>Declare</hi> at their <hi>Hall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yet at a Puſh not one ſtir.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Sir Arthur</hi> vow'd, hee'l treat 'm,</l>
                  <l>Far worſe than the men of <hi>Cheſter:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He's <hi>Bold,</hi> now they're <hi>Cow'd,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But he was nothing ſo <hi>Lowd</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When he lay in the ditch at Lester.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Lord</hi> hath left <hi>John Lambert,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And the <hi>Spirit, Feak's Anointed:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But why, Oh Lord,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Hast thou ſheathed thy Sword?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Lo, thy Saints are diſappointed.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Tho' Sir <hi>Henry</hi> be departed:</l>
                  <l>Sir <hi>John</hi> makes good the place now,</l>
                  <l>And to help out the work</l>
                  <l>Of the Glorious <hi>Kirk,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Our <hi>Brethren</hi> march apace too.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>While <hi>Divines,</hi> and <hi>States-men wrangle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Let the <hi>Rump-ridden</hi> Nation bite on't,</l>
                  <pb n="69" facs="tcp:115486:38"/>
                  <l>There are none but we</l>
                  <l>That are ſure to go free,</l>
                  <l>For the Souldier's ſtill in the right-on't.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If our <hi>Maſters</hi> w'ont ſupply us,</l>
                  <l>With <hi>Money, Food,</hi> and <hi>Clothing:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Let the <hi>State</hi> look to't,</l>
                  <l>Wee'l find one that will do't,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Let him Live,</hi> — wee'l not damn for nothing.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Then away with the Laws,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And the</hi> Good old Cauſe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're talk o' the</hi> Rump, <hi>or the</hi> Charter,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>'Tis the Caſh does the feat,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>All the</hi> reſt's <hi>but a</hi> Cheat,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Without</hi> That, <hi>there's no</hi> Faith <hi>nor</hi> Quarter.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>A Relation of a Quaker, that, to the ſhame of his profeſſion, attempted to Bugger a <hi>Mare</hi> near <hi>Colcheſter.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>ALl in the land of <hi>Eſſex,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Near <hi>Colcheſter</hi> the zealous,</l>
                  <l>On the ſide of a Bank</l>
                  <l>VVas plaid ſuch a prank</l>
                  <l>As would make a Stone-horſe jealous.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="70" facs="tcp:115486:39"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Help <hi>Woodcock, Fox,</hi> and <hi>Nailer,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For brother <hi>Green</hi>'s a Stallion;</l>
                  <l>Now alas what hope</l>
                  <l>Of converting the Pope,</l>
                  <l>VVhen a Quaker turns <hi>Italian.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Unto our whole profeſſion,</l>
                  <l>A ſcandall 'twill be counted,</l>
                  <l>VVhen 'tis talk'd with diſdain,</l>
                  <l>Amongſt the profane,</l>
                  <l>How Brother <hi>Green</hi> was mounted.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And in the good time of <hi>Chriſtmas,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which though the Saints have damn'd all,</l>
                  <l>Yet when did they hear</l>
                  <l>Of a damn'd Cavalier</l>
                  <l>E're plaid ſuch a <hi>Chriſtmas</hi> Gamball?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Had thy fleſh, O <hi>Green,</hi> been pamper'd</l>
                  <l>With any Cates unhallow'd;</l>
                  <l>Hadſt thou ſweeten'd thy gums</l>
                  <l>With pottage of plums,</l>
                  <l>Or prophane minc'd pie hadſt ſwallow'd.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Roll'd up in wanton Swines fleſh,</l>
                  <l>The Fiend might have crept into thee;</l>
                  <l>Then fulneſſe of gut</l>
                  <l>Might have made thee rue,</l>
                  <l>And the devill ſo have rid through thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="71" facs="tcp:115486:39"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>But alas, he had been feaſted</l>
                  <l>With a ſpirituall Collation,</l>
                  <l>By our frugall Mayor,</l>
                  <l>Who can dine with a Prayer,</l>
                  <l>And ſup with an Exhortation.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Twas meer impulſe of ſpirit,</l>
                  <l>Though he us'd the weapon carnall.</l>
                  <l>Filly Foal, quoth he,</l>
                  <l>My Bride thou ſhalt be:</l>
                  <l>Now how this is lawfull, learn all.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For if no reſpect of perſons</l>
                  <l>Be due 'mongſt the ſons of <hi>Adam,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In a large extent</l>
                  <l>Then may it be meant,</l>
                  <l>That a <hi>Mare</hi>'s as good as a <hi>Madam.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then without more Ceremony,</l>
                  <l>Nor Bonnet vail'd, nor Kiſt her,</l>
                  <l>He took her by force</l>
                  <l>For better for worſe,</l>
                  <l>And he us'd her like a Siſter.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now when in ſuch a Saddle</l>
                  <l>A Saint will needs be riding,</l>
                  <l>Though I dare not ſay</l>
                  <l>'Tis a falling away,</l>
                  <l>May there not be ſome back-ſliding?</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="72" facs="tcp:115486:40"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>No ſurely, quoth <hi>James Naylor,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Twas but an inſurrection</l>
                  <l>Of the carnall part;</l>
                  <l>For a Quaker in heart</l>
                  <l>Can never loſe Perfection.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For ſo our <note n="*" place="margin">Hiſt. of <hi>Jeſuitiſm.</hi>
                     </note> Maſters teach us,</l>
                  <l>The intent being well directed;</l>
                  <l>Though the Devill trapan</l>
                  <l>The Adamicall man,</l>
                  <l>The Saint ſtands uninfected.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But yet a Pagan-Jury</l>
                  <l>Still judges what's intended;</l>
                  <l>Then ſay what we can,</l>
                  <l>Brother <hi>Green</hi>'s outward man</l>
                  <l>I fear will be ſuſpended.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And our Adopted Siſter</l>
                  <l>Will find no better quarter;</l>
                  <l>But when him we Inroule</l>
                  <l>For a Saint, Filly Foal</l>
                  <l>Shall paſſe at leaſt for a Martyr.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now <hi>Rome</hi> that ſpirituall <hi>Sodom</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>No longer is thy debtor;</l>
                  <l>O <hi>Colcheſter</hi> now,</l>
                  <l>Who's <hi>Sodom</hi> but thou?</l>
                  <l>Even according to the Letter.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="73" facs="tcp:115486:40"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Help <hi>Woodcock, Fox,</hi> and <hi>Nailor,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For Brother <hi>Green</hi>'s a Stallion;</l>
                  <l>Now alas what hope</l>
                  <l>Of converting the Pope,</l>
                  <l>When a Quaker turns <hi>Italian?</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <head>The Four-legg'd Quaker,</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of the Dog and Elder's Maid; Or, The Lady's fall.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>ALL that have two or but one Eare,</l>
                  <l>(I dare not tell ye half)</l>
                  <l>You of an <hi>Eſſex</hi> Colt ſhall hear</l>
                  <l>Will ſhame their very <hi>Calf.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In <hi>Horſley</hi> fields neer <hi>Colcheſter</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>A <hi>Quaker</hi> would turn Trooper;</l>
                  <l>He caught a Foal and mounted her</l>
                  <l>(O baſe!) below the Crupper.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help, Lords and Commons, once more help,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>O ſend us Knives and Daggers!</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For if the Quakers be not gelt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Your Troops will have the Staggers.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>RALPH GREEN,</hi> (it was this Varlet's name)</l>
                  <l>Of <hi>Colcheſter</hi> you'l ſwear,</l>
                  <l>For thence the <hi>four-legg'd Elder</hi> came,</l>
                  <l>Was ever ſuch a Pair!</l>
                  <pb n="74" facs="tcp:115486:41"/>
                  <l>But though 'twas foul, 'tween <hi>Swaſh</hi> and <hi>Jane,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet this is ten times worſe,</l>
                  <l>For then a Dog did play the Man,</l>
                  <l>But Man now play'd the Horſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Owner of the Colt was nigh,</l>
                  <l>(Obſerving their Embrace)</l>
                  <l>And drawing neerer did eſpie</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Quaker</hi>'s ſorrell Face:</l>
                  <l>My Foal is raviſh'd (then he cryes,</l>
                  <l>And fiercely at him ran)</l>
                  <l>Thou Rogue, I'le have thee halter'd twice,</l>
                  <l>As Horſe and eke as Man!</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Ah Devill, do'ſt thou tremble? now</l>
                  <l>'Tis ſore againſt thy will;</l>
                  <l>For Mares and preaching Ladies know</l>
                  <l>Thou haſt a Colt's tooth ſtill:</l>
                  <l>But mine's not guilty of this Fact,</l>
                  <l>She was by thee compelled;</l>
                  <l>Poor thing, whom no man ever Back't,</l>
                  <l>Thou wickedly haſt Bellied.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O Friend, (ſaid <hi>GREEN,</hi> with ſighs and groans)</l>
                  <l>Let this thy wrath appeaſe!</l>
                  <l>(And gave him then eight new half-Crowns</l>
                  <l>To make him hold his peace)</l>
                  <pb n="75" facs="tcp:115486:41"/>
                  <l>The man reply'd, Though I for this</l>
                  <l>Conceal thy Hugger Mugger,</l>
                  <l>Do'ſt think it lawfull for a Piece</l>
                  <l>A filly Foal to Bugger?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Maſter ſaw his Colt defil'd,</l>
                  <l>Which vext his ſoul with doubt;</l>
                  <l>For if his Filly prov'd with Child,</l>
                  <l>He knew all would come out:</l>
                  <l>Then he afreſh began to rave,</l>
                  <l>(For all his Money-taking)</l>
                  <l>Neighbours, ſaith he, I took this Knave</l>
                  <l>I'th very act of <hi>Quaking!</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help, Lords and Commons, once more help,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>O ſend us Knives and Daggers!</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For if the Quakers be not gelt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Your Troops will have the Staggers.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then to the Pinfold (Gaol I mean)</l>
                  <l>They dragg'd him by the Mane,</l>
                  <l>They call'd him Beaſt, and call'd her Quean;</l>
                  <l>As if ſhe had been <hi>Jane.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>O ſtone him (all the Women cry'd)</l>
                  <l>Nay, Geld him (which is worſe)</l>
                  <l>Who ſcorn'd us all and took a Bride</l>
                  <l>That's Daughter to a Horſe!</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Colt was ſilent all this while,</l>
                  <l>And therefore 'twas no Rape,</l>
                  <pb n="76" facs="tcp:115486:42"/>
                  <l>The Virgin-Foal he did beguile,</l>
                  <l>And ſo intends to eſcape.</l>
                  <l>For though he got her in a Ditch</l>
                  <l>Where ſhe could not revolt,</l>
                  <l>Yet he had no <hi>Scot'ſh Spur</hi> nor Switch</l>
                  <l>To ride the willing Colt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O <hi>Eſſex, Eſſex, England</hi>'s pride,</l>
                  <l>Go burn this long-tail'd Quean,</l>
                  <l>For though the <hi>Thames</hi> runs by thy ſide,</l>
                  <l>It cannot waſh thee clean!</l>
                  <l>'Tis not thy Bleating Son's complaints,</l>
                  <l>Hold forth ſuch wanton courſes,</l>
                  <l>Thy Oyſters hint the very Saints</l>
                  <l>To horn the very Horſes.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Though they ſalute not in the ſtreet</l>
                  <l>(Becauſe they are our Maſters)</l>
                  <l>'Tis now reveal'd why <hi>Quakers</hi> meet</l>
                  <l>In Meadows, Woods, and Paſtures.</l>
                  <l>But Horſ-men, Mare-men, all and ſome</l>
                  <l>Who Man and Beaſt perplex,</l>
                  <l>Not only from Eaſt-<hi>Horſley</hi> come,</l>
                  <l>But from <hi>Weſt-Middle-Sex.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Alas you know by Man's fleſh came</l>
                  <l>The <hi>foul diſeaſe</hi> to <hi>Naples,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="77" facs="tcp:115486:42"/>
                  <l>And now we fear the very ſame</l>
                  <l>Is broke into our Stables;</l>
                  <l>For death hath ſtoln ſo many ſteeds</l>
                  <l>From Prince and Peer and Carrier,</l>
                  <l>That this new Murrain rather needs</l>
                  <l>A <note n="*" place="bottom">Phyſician to the <hi>Earl</hi> of <hi>Pembroke,</hi> who is no <hi>Quaker</hi> nor <hi>Quacker.</hi>
                     </note> 
                     <hi>FARRAR</hi> than a Farrier.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Nay if this <hi>GREEN</hi> within the Walls</l>
                  <l>Of <hi>Colcheſter</hi> left forces,</l>
                  <l>Thoſe Cavaliers were Caniballs,</l>
                  <l>Eating his human Horſes!</l>
                  <l>But ſome make Man their <hi>ſecond courſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(In cool Blood will not ſpare)</l>
                  <l>Who butcher Men and favour Horſe</l>
                  <l>Will couple with a Mare.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This <hi>Centaur,</hi> unquoth <hi>Other</hi> thing,</l>
                  <l>VVill make a dreadfull Breach:</l>
                  <l>Yet though an Aſſe may Speak or <note n="*" place="bottom">A new Sect of young Men and Women, who pray, eat, and ſing <hi>ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempore.</hi>
                     </note> Sing,</l>
                  <l>O let not Horſes Preach!</l>
                  <l>But Bridle ſuch wild Colts who can</l>
                  <l>VVhen they'l obey no Summons,</l>
                  <l>For things begot 'tween Mare and Man</l>
                  <l>Are neither Lords nor Commons.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="78" facs="tcp:115486:43"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>O <hi>Elders, Independents</hi> too,</l>
                  <l>Though all your Powers combin'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Quakers</hi> will grow too ſtrong for you,</l>
                  <l>Now Horſe and Man are joyn'd:</l>
                  <l>VVhile Cavaliers, poor fooliſh Rogues,</l>
                  <l>Know only Maids Affairs,</l>
                  <l>Shee-Presbyters can deal with Dogs,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Quaking</hi> Men with Mares.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now as when <hi>Milan</hi> Town was rear'd,</l>
                  <l>A monſtrous Sow untam'd</l>
                  <l>VVith back half-Hair half-VVool appear'd,</l>
                  <l>'Twas <hi>Mediolanum</hi> nam'd:</l>
                  <l>So <hi>Colcheſter</hi> muſt have recourſe</l>
                  <l>To ſome ſuch four-legg'd Siſter,</l>
                  <l>For ſure as <hi>Horſley</hi> comes from Horſe</l>
                  <l>From Colt 'twas call'd <hi>Col-cheſter.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>Help, Lords and Commons, once more help,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>O ſend us Knives and Daggers!</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For if the Quakers be not gelt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Your Troops will have the Staggers.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="79" facs="tcp:115486:43"/>
               <head>St. GEORGE and the DRAGON. ANGLICE <hi>MERCURIUS POETICUS.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>The Old Soldier of the Queens,</hi> &amp;c.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>NEws, News: — Here's the <hi>Occurrences,</hi> and a new <hi>Mercurius:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>A Dialogue betwixt <hi>Hazelrig</hi> the <hi>Baffl'd,</hi> and <hi>Arthur</hi> the <hi>Furious:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With <hi>Ireton</hi>'s readings upon <hi>Legitimate</hi> and <hi>Spurious,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Proving that a <hi>Saint</hi> may be the <hi>Son of a Whore,</hi> for the ſatisfaction of the Curious.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump inſatiate as the Sea,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Libera nos Domine.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here's the true reaſon of the <hi>City's Infatuation:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ireton</hi> has made it <hi>drunck</hi> with the <hi>Cup of Abomination:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That is, — <hi>the cup of the Whore,</hi> after the <hi>Geneva Interpretation:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which, with the juice of <hi>Tichburn</hi>'s <hi>Grapes,</hi> muſt needs cauſe <hi>Intoxication.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here's the <hi>Whipper whipt</hi> by a Friend to <hi>George,</hi> that whipp'd <hi>Jack,</hi> that whipp'd the <hi>Breech,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That whipp'd the <hi>Nation, as long as it could ſtand over it:</hi> — After which</l>
                  <l>It was it ſelfe <hi>Re-jerk'd,</hi> by the ſage Author <hi>of this Speech:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="80" facs="tcp:115486:44"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Me-thinks a Rump ſhould go as well with a Scotch ſpur, as with a Switch.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This <hi>Rump</hi> hath many a <hi>Rotten and unruly Member:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Give the <hi>General</hi> the <hi>Oath,</hi> cries one; — but (his Conſcience being a little <hi>tender,</hi>)</l>
                  <l>I'le <hi>Abjure</hi> you, with a Horſe-pox, quoth <hi>George,</hi> — and make you remember</l>
                  <l>The <hi>'Leaventh</hi> of <hi>February,</hi> longer than the <hi>Fifth</hi> of <hi>November.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>VVith that — <hi>Monck</hi> leaves <hi>(in Rump aſſembled) — the Three Eſtates.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But oh, — how the <hi>Citizens hugg'd</hi> him for <hi>breaking</hi> down their <hi>Gates,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Tearing</hi> up their <hi>Poſts,</hi> and <hi>Chains,</hi> and for <hi>Clapping up their Mates,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>(When they ſaw, that he brought them Plaſters for their broken Pates.)</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>In truth, this Rufle put the Town in great <hi>diſorder;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Some <hi>Knaves (in Office) ſmil'd,</hi> — expecting 'twould go furder;</l>
                  <l>But at the laſt, — my Life on't, <hi>George</hi> is no <hi>Rumper,</hi> — ſaid the <hi>Recorder:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For there never was either <hi>Honeſt Man,</hi> or <hi>Monck of that Order.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And ſo it prov'd, for <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> ſayes the Generall, I'le make you amends:</l>
                  <pb n="81" facs="tcp:115486:44"/>
                  <l>Our <hi>Greeting</hi> was a little <hi>untoward,</hi> but wee'l <hi>part Friends,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>A little time ſhall ſhew you which way my Deſign tends,</l>
                  <l>And that, <hi>beſides the good of Church and State, I have no other ends.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His <hi>Excellence</hi> had no ſooner paſs'd this <hi>Declaration</hi> and <hi>Promiſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But in ſteps <hi>Secretary Scot, — the Rump</hi>'s <hi>man Thomas,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With <hi>Luke,</hi> their lame Evangeliſt, — (the Devil keep 'um from us,)</l>
                  <l>To ſhew <hi>Monck what precious Members of Church and State the Bumm ha's.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now comes the <hi>Supplication of the Members under the Rod,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nay, <hi>My Lord, (cryes the Brewers Clerk) — good my Lord,</hi> — for the Love of God,</l>
                  <l>Conſider <hi>yourſelf, us,</hi> — and this <hi>poor Nation,</hi> and that <hi>Tyrant Abroad;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Don't leave us, — but <hi>George</hi> gave him a <hi>Shrugg,</hi> inſtead of a <hi>Nodd.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This mortall <hi>Silence</hi> was followed with a moſt hideous <hi>Noyſe</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of <hi>Free-Parliament Bells,</hi> and <hi>Rump-confounding Boyes:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="82" facs="tcp:115486:45"/>
                  <l>Crying, <hi>Gueld</hi> the <hi>Rogues, Sindg</hi> their <hi>Tails,</hi> — when with a low Voyce,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Fire and Sword,</hi> by this Light, cryes <hi>Tom,</hi> let's look to our <hi>Toyes.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Never were wretched <hi>Members</hi> in ſo ſad a Plight:</l>
                  <l>Some were <hi>Broyld,</hi> — ſome <hi>Roaſted,</hi> — others <hi>Burnt out-right,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nay, againſt <hi>Rumps,</hi> ſo <hi>Pittileſſe</hi> was their <hi>Rage</hi> and <hi>Spite,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That <hi>not a Citizen would kiſſe his wife that Night.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>By this time, <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hell</hi> appear'd in the ghaſtly <hi>Looks,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of <hi>Scot,</hi> and <hi>Robinſon;</hi> (thoſe <hi>Legiſlative Rooks</hi>)</l>
                  <l>And it muſt needs put the <hi>Rump</hi> moſt damnably off the Hooks,</l>
                  <l>To ſee, that <hi>when God has ſent meat, the Devil ſhould ſend Cooks.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But <hi>Providence,</hi> their old friend, brought theſe Saints off, at Laſt,</l>
                  <l>And through the <hi>Pikes,</hi> and the <hi>Flames, un-diſ-membred</hi> they Paſt,</l>
                  <l>Although (God wot) with many <hi>ſtruglings,</hi> and much <hi>Haſt.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(For — <hi>Members,</hi> — or <hi>no Members,</hi> was but a meaſuring Caſt.)</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Being come to <hi>Whitehall;</hi> — there's the diſmall mone:</l>
                  <pb n="83" facs="tcp:115486:45"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Let Monck be damn'd,</hi> cries <hi>Arthur,</hi> in a terrible tone:</l>
                  <l>That <hi>Traytor: — and thoſe Cuckoldly Rogues that ſet him on:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(But, tho' the Knight <hi>ſpits Blood,</hi> 'tis obſerv'd that he <hi>Draws none</hi>)</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Plague Bawle you, cries <hi>Harry Martin,</hi> you have brought us to this condition,</l>
                  <l>You muſt be canting, and be Pox'd, — with your <hi>Bare-bones Petition,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And take in that <hi>Bull-headed, ſplay-footed Member of the Circumciſion,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That Bacon-fac'd Jew, Corbet: that ſon of Perdition.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then in ſteps <hi>Driv'ling Mounſon,</hi> to take up the Squabble:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That Lord,</hi> which firſt taught the uſe of the <hi>Wooden Dagger, and Ladle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>He,</hi> — that out-does <hi>Jack Pudding,</hi> at a <hi>Cuſtard,</hi> or a <hi>Cawdle:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And were the Beſt <hi>Fool</hi> in <hi>Europe,</hi> but that he wants a <hi>Bawble.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>More was ſaid, to little Purpoſe: the next news, is — a <hi>Declaration</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>From the <hi>Rump;</hi> for a <hi rend="blackletterType">Free-State,</hi> according to the <hi rend="blackletterType">Covenant</hi> of the Nation,</l>
                  <l>And a <hi rend="blackletterType">Free-Parliament,</hi> under <hi rend="blackletterType">Oath,</hi> and <hi rend="blackletterType">Qualification,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="84" facs="tcp:115486:46"/>
                  <l>Where none ſhall be <hi>Elect,</hi> but Members of <hi>Reprobation.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here's the <hi>Tail Firk'd; a Piece acted lately with great applauſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With a <hi>Plea</hi> for the <hi>Prerogative Breech,</hi> and the <hi>Good Old Gauſe:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Proving, that <hi>Rumps,</hi> and <hi>Members,</hi> are <hi>antienter than Laws:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And that a <hi>Bumm Divided,</hi> is never the worſe for the <hi>Flawes.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From the Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But all things have their Period, and Fate,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>An Act of Parliament diſſolves a Rump of State:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Members</hi> grow <hi>weak;</hi> and <hi>Tails themſelves run out of Date:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yet thou ſhalt not Dye; <hi>(Dear Breech)</hi> thy <hi>Fame</hi> I'le celebrate.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Here lies a Pack of Saints,</hi> that did their <hi>Souls,</hi> and <hi>Country Sell</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Dirt; The Devil was their good Lord:</hi> him they ſerv'd Well;</l>
                  <l>By his <hi>Advice,</hi> they <hi>Stood,</hi> and <hi>Acted:</hi> and by his <hi>Preſident</hi> they <hi>Fell,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(Like <hi>Lucifer</hi>) making but <hi>one ſtep</hi> betwixt <hi>Heaven,</hi> and <hi>Hell.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>From a Rump inſatiate as the Sea,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Liberaſti nos Domine.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="ballad">
               <pb n="85" facs="tcp:115486:46"/>
               <head>A Dialogue betwixt <hi>Tom</hi> and <hi>Dick,</hi> The former a <hi>Country-Man,</hi> the other a <hi>Citizen,</hi> Preſented to His Excellency and the Councill of State at Drapers-Hall, in London, <hi>March</hi> 28. 1660.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>Ile never love thee more.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> NOw would I give my life to ſee,</l>
                  <l>This wondrous man of might.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick.</hi> Do'ſt ſee that <hi>Jolly Lad?</hi> That's he;</l>
                  <l>I'le warrant him he's <hi>right.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Ther's a <hi>true Trojan</hi> in his <hi>Face:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Obſerve him o're and o're.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. Come</hi> Tom; <hi>If ever George be baſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He's none of that <hi>Fantaſtique brood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That <hi>murther</hi> while they <hi>pray:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That <hi>truſſe</hi> and <hi>cheat</hi> us, <hi>for our good;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>(All, in a godly way.)</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He <hi>Drinks</hi> no <hi>Blood,</hi> and <hi>they</hi> no <hi>Sack</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Into their <hi>gutts</hi> will <hi>poure.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But if GEORGE does not the knack;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt good-fellow more</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His quiet <hi>Conſcience</hi> needs no <hi>guard;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He's <hi>brave,</hi> but full of <hi>pitty.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="86" facs="tcp:115486:47"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> Yet, by your leave, he <hi>knock'd ſo hard,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>H'ad like t'awak'd the Citty.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. Fool,</hi> 'Twas the <hi>Rump</hi> that let a <hi>Fart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Chains</hi> and <hi>Gates</hi> it <hi>tore.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But if GEORGE beares not a true heart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> Your <hi>Citty-blades</hi> are <hi>cunning Rooks,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>How rarely you <hi>collogue</hi> him?</l>
                  <l>But when your <hi>Gates</hi> flew off the <hi>Hooks,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>You did as much <hi>be-rogue</hi> him.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick.</hi> Pug'h. — 'Twas the <hi>Rump</hi> did onely <hi>feel,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>blowes</hi> the City <hi>bore,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But if</hi> GEORGE <hi>be'nt as true as Steel,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come, by this <hi>Hand wee'l crack a quart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thou'lt <hi>pledge his health</hi> I trow.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom. Tope Boy,</hi> Dick — A <hi>luſty Diſh my heart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Away w'ot;</hi> Tom. — <hi>Let it go.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Drench me you ſlave in a <hi>full Bowle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I'le take't, an 'twere a <hi>ſcore,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. Nay, if</hi> GEORGE <hi>be'nt a hearty Soul,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> But heark you, Sirrah, we're too <hi>loud,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Hee'l <hi>hang</hi> us, by and by.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick.</hi> Me 'thinks, he ſhould be vengeance <hi>proud?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>No more then <hi>thee,</hi> or I.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> Why then I'le give him the beſt <hi>Blade,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That ere the <hi>Bilbo</hi> wore,</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="87" facs="tcp:115486:47"/>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. If</hi> GEORGE <hi>prove not a Bonney Lad,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> 'Twas well he <hi>came, we'd mawll'd the Tail;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>— We've all <hi>thrown</hi> up our <hi>Farms.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And from the <hi>Musket,</hi> to the <hi>Flayl,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Put all our men in <hi>Arms.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Girles</hi> had ta'ne the <hi>Members</hi> down,</l>
                  <l>Ne're ſaw ſuch things before.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. If</hi> George <hi>ſpeak not the Town our own,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick.</hi> But pre'thee, are the Folk ſo <hi>mad,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> So mad, ſay'ſt; — They 're <hi>undone,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>There's not a <hi>penny</hi> to be had;</l>
                  <l>And ev'ry Mother's Sonne</l>
                  <l>Muſt fight, if he intend to <hi>eate,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Grow <hi>valiant,</hi> now he is <hi>poor.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. Come — yet if</hi> George <hi>don't do the Feat,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> Why <hi>Richard,</hi> 'tis a <hi>Deviliſh thing.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We're not left worth a groat.</l>
                  <l>My <hi>Doll</hi> has <hi>ſold</hi> her <hi>wedding-ring,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>Sue</hi> has <hi>pawnd</hi> her <hi>Coat.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Sniv'ling Rogues</hi> abus'd our <hi>Squire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And call'd our <hi>Miſtreſſe Whore.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick.</hi> Yet — if George <hi>don't what we deſire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="88" facs="tcp:115486:48"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> By this good day; I did but <hi>ſpeak,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>They took my Py-ball'd Mare;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And put the Carri'on wench to th' ſqueak.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>(Things go againſt the Hair.)</l>
                  <l>Our <hi>Prick-ar'd, Cor'nell</hi> looks as <hi>bigg</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Still,</hi> as he did <hi>before.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Cho.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. And yet if</hi> George <hi>don't humme his Gigg,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Faith <hi>Tom: our Caſe</hi> is much at one;</l>
                  <l>We're broak for want of <hi>Trade;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Our <hi>City</hi>'s <hi>baffled,</hi> and <hi>undone,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Betwixt the <hi>Rump,</hi> and <hi>Blade.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We've emptied both our <hi>Veins</hi> and <hi>Baggs,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Upon a <hi>Factious Score.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>If</hi> George <hi>Compaſſion not our Raggs,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> But what doeſt think ſhould be the <hi>Cauſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whence all theſe Miſchiefs ſpring?</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Dick. Our damned breach of Oaths and Laws;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Our Murther of the</hi> King.</l>
                  <l>We have been <hi>Slaves</hi> ſince <hi>CHARL'S</hi> his <hi>Reign,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We liv'd like <hi>Lords</hi> before.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>If</hi> George <hi>don't ſet all right again,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> Our <hi>Vicar — (And bee's one that knows)</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Told me once, — I know what: —</l>
                  <l>(And yet the Thief is woundly <hi>Cloſe</hi>)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Rich.</hi> 'Tis all the <hi>better;</hi> — That.</l>
                  <pb n="89" facs="tcp:115486:48"/>
                  <l>Ha's too much <hi>Honeſty</hi> and <hi>Witt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To let his <hi>tongue run o're:</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>If This prove not a lucky hitt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Shall's <hi>ask</hi> him, what he <hi>means</hi> to <hi>do?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> — 'Good faith, with all my heart;</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Thou</hi> mak'ſt the <hi>better Leg</hi> o' th' Two:</l>
                  <l>Take <hi>thou</hi> the <hi>better part.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I'le <hi>follow,</hi> if thou't lead the <hi>van.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Rich.</hi> Content; — <hi>I'le march before.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>If GEORGE <hi>prove not a Gallant man,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>My Lord: — in <hi>us</hi> the <hi>Nation craves</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But what you're <hi>bound to do.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tom.</hi> — We have <hi>liv'd Drudges. Ric.</hi> — And <hi>we Slaves;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Both.</hi> We would not <hi>die</hi> ſo <hi>too.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <head>Chorus.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Reſtore us but our Laws agen;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Th' unborn ſhall thee adore:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>If GEORGE <hi>denies us his Amen;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Ne're truſt Good-fellow more.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:115486:49"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
